<Think>
Okay, so I need to match these radioactive decay processes in List-I with the correct emitted particles in List-II.
Hmm, let's start by understanding each decay process and what particles they might emit.
First, I remember that when elements undergo radioactive decay, they emit alpha particles (which are helium nuclei, so charge +2 and mass number 4) or beta particles (which are electrons for beta minus or positrons for beta plus).
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Understanding the effect of alpha decay on atomic and mass numbers.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Understanding the mechanism and effect of beta minus decay.
</Outline>
<Outline>
3: Understanding the mechanism and effect of beta plus decay.
</Outline>
<Outline>
4: Evaluating electron capture as an alternative decay process.
</Outline>
<Outline>
5: Identifying the absence of electron capture from the listed emission options.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Alpha decay results in the atomic number decreasing by 2 and the mass number decreasing by 4.
</Path>
<Path>
2: Beta minus decay involves a neutron converting into a proton, accompanied by the emission of an electron (beta minus particle), which leads to an increase in the atomic number by 1.
</Path>
<Path>
3: In beta plus decay, a proton transforms into a neutron, emits a positron, and consequently, the atomic number decreases by 1.
</Path>
<Path>
4: Electron capture is considered as another potential nuclear decay process.
</Path>
<Path>
5: Electron capture also causes a decrease in atomic number by 1, and it is not provided as an emission option in List-II.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
Alpha decay reduces the mass number (A) by 4 and the atomic number (Z) by 2. Beta minus decay increases Z by 1, while A remains unchanged. Beta plus decay decreases Z by 1, with A also remaining unchanged. Electron capture, which similarly decreases Z by 1, is not provided as an emission option in the list.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Let me go process by process.
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Analyze the decay of Uranium-238 to Protactinium-234 (Process P) to determine the emitted particles.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Analyze the decay of Lead-214 to Lead-210 (Process Q) to determine the emitted particles.
</Outline>
<Outline>
3: Analyze the decay of Thallium-210 to Lead-206 (Process R) to determine the emitted particles.
</Outline>
<Outline>
4: Analyze the decay of Protactinium-228 to Radium-224 (Process S) to determine the emitted particles.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Let's start with P: Uranium-238 decaying to Protactinium-234.
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1.1: Identify the initial nucleus for process P.
</Outline>
<Outline>
1.2: Identify the final nucleus for process P.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1.1: Identify initial nucleus: Uranium-238 (Z=92, A=238).
</Path>
<Path>
1.2: Identify final nucleus: Protactinium-234 (Z=91, A=234).
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The initial nucleus for process P is U-238 (Z=92, A=238). The final nucleus is Pa-234 (Z=91, A=234).
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1.1: Calculate the change in atomic number (Z) for process P.
</Outline>
<Outline>
1.2: Calculate the change in mass number (A) for process P.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1.1: Calculate change in Z: ΔZ = -1.
</Path>
<Path>
1.2: Calculate change in A: ΔA = -4.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
For process P, the atomic number decreases by 1 (ΔZ = -1), and the mass number decreases by 4 (ΔA = -4).
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Wait, mass number decreases by 4—so that suggests an alpha decay, which reduces mass by 4 and atomic number by 2.
But here the atomic number decreased by 1.
That’s a problem because if it’s an alpha decay, the atomic number should go down by 2.
Hmmm.
Maybe beta plus decay?
Wait, but beta plus decay would actually decrease atomic number by 1.
Wait, if we have Uranium (92) to Protactinium (91), that's a decrease of 1 in atomic number.
So maybe this is a beta plus decay?
But wait, beta plus decay involves converting a proton into a neutron, which would decrease atomic number by 1.
But usually, beta plus decay is more common in proton-rich nuclei.
The options are combinations of alpha and beta particles.
Or maybe there was an alpha emission and a beta plus?
Wait, let's think again.
The mass decrease is 4, which suggests an alpha emission.
But the atomic number only went down by 1.
If the Alpha emission would cause the atomic number to decrease by 2, but here it's only 1, then there must be another decay after the alpha decay.
Maybe after the alpha decay, some beta plus decay.
Let me calculate: If Uranium-238 emits an alpha particle (He-4), then the mass would go to 234, and the atomic number to 90 (since 92 - 2 = 90).
But here the product is Protactinium-234 (atomic number 91).
So after the alpha decay, suppose you have something at 90, but then it converts to 91.
So that would require a beta minus decay (which increases atomic number by 1).
But then how?
Wait, no.
Wait, original is 92 U → 91 Pa.
So the atomic number goes from 92 to 91.
So if an alpha decay happened (atomic number 92 - 2 = 90), but then we get to 91, which is an increase by 1.
So that would require a beta minus decay?
Because beta minus increases atomic number by 1.
So perhaps, first an alpha decay (mass down 4, atomic number down 2 to 90), then a beta minus decay (atomic number up by 1 to 91).
Therefore, total particles emitted: one alpha and one beta minus.
So for process P, the emitted particles would be one alpha and one beta minus.
Let's look at List-II options.
Option 4 is one alpha and one beta minus.
So P should be matched with 4.
</Path>
<Path>
2: Next, process Q: Lead-214 decays to Lead-210.
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
2.1: Identify the initial nucleus for process Q.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2.2: Identify the final nucleus for process Q.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
2.1: Identify initial nucleus: Lead-214 (Z=82, A=214).
</Path>
<Path>
2.2: Identify final nucleus: Lead-210 (Z=82, A=210).
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The initial nucleus for process Q is Pb-214 (Z=82, A=214). The final nucleus is Pb-210 (Z=82, A=210).
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
2.1: Calculate the change in atomic number (Z) for process Q.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2.2: Calculate the change in mass number (A) for process Q.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
2.1: Calculate change in Z: ΔZ = 0.
</Path>
<Path>
2.2: Calculate change in A: ΔA = -4.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
For process Q, the atomic number is unchanged (ΔZ = 0), and the mass number decreases by 4 (ΔA = -4).
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
The element is still lead (Pb), so atomic number remains 82.
Mass number decreases by 4, which suggests an alpha decay.
Wait, but atomic number remains the same.
But alpha decay would reduce the atomic number by 2 and mass by 4.
But here atomic number stays the same.
So maybe two alpha decays followed by two beta decays?
Wait, no.
Wait, if it's going from Pb-214 to Pb-210, losing 4 mass units.
So 214 - 4 = 210.
So an alpha decay would reduce the mass by 4, but atomic number by 2.
To retain the same atomic number, how?
Maybe an alpha decay and two beta minus decays?
Wait, first, if the nucleus emits an alpha particle (mass -4, atomic number -2).
Then the product would have atomic number 80 (82 - 2).
To get back to 82, you need two beta minus decays.
Each beta minus increases atomic number by 1, so two beta minus would give atomic number 82 (80 + 2).
So in total, 1 alpha and 2 beta minus particles.
So emitting one alpha and two betas.
But wait, looking at the list-II options: Option 3 says two beta minus and one alpha.
Yes, same thing.
So that would be Option 3.
So Q would be 3.
Let me confirm: Pb-214 → Pb-210.
Change in atomic number: 82→82.
So if we have an alpha decay, mass down by 4, atomic number down by 2 to 80.
To get back to 82, need two beta minus.
So, 2 beta minus and 1 alpha.
Hence, Q is 3.
</Path>
<Path>
3: Moving to R: Thallium-210 (atomic number 81) decays to Lead-206 (atomic number 82).
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
3.1: Identify the initial nucleus for process R.
</Outline>
<Outline>
3.2: Identify the final nucleus for process R.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
3.1: Identify initial nucleus: Thallium-210 (Z=81, A=210).
</Path>
<Path>
3.2: Identify final nucleus: Lead-206 (Z=82, A=206).
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The initial nucleus for process R is Tl-210 (Z=81, A=210). The final nucleus is Pb-206 (Z=82, A=206).
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
3.1: Calculate the change in atomic number (Z) for process R.
</Outline>
<Outline>
3.2: Calculate the change in mass number (A) for process R.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
3.1: Calculate change in Z: ΔZ = +1.
</Path>
<Path>
3.2: Calculate change in A: ΔA = -4.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
For process R, the atomic number increases by 1 (ΔZ = +1), and the mass number decreases by 4 (ΔA = -4).
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Mass number decreases by 4 (from 210 to 206), which suggests one alpha decay.
But atomic number increases by 1 (from 81 to 82).
Let me analyze.
If Thallium-210 emits an alpha, mass becomes 206, atomic number 79 (81 - 2).
But the final atomic number is 82.
So from 79 to 82, you need an increase of 3.
Which would be three beta minus decays (each beta gives +1).
So total particles would be 1 alpha and 3 beta minus.
Check List-II: Option 2 is three beta minus particles and one alpha.
So R is 2.
Wait, but hold on.
Let me verify again.
R: from 81 Tl to 82 Pb.
Mass change: 210→206: alpha (mass -4), so atomic number goes from 81 to 79.
Then, from 79 to 82 would need three beta minus: each beta increases atomic number by 1.
So yes, total three beta minus and one alpha.
So Option 2.
Hence, R matches with 2.
</Path>
<Path>
4: Then S: Protactinium-228 (atomic number 91) decaying to Radium-224 (atomic number 88).
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
4.1: Identify the initial nucleus for process S.
</Outline>
<Outline>
4.2: Identify the final nucleus for process S.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
4.1: Identify initial nucleus: Protactinium-228 (Z=91, A=228).
</Path>
<Path>
4.2: Identify final nucleus: Radium-224 (Z=88, A=224).
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The initial nucleus for process S is Pa-228 (Z=91, A=228). The final nucleus is Ra-224 (Z=88, A=224).
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
4.1: Calculate the change in atomic number (Z) for process S.
</Outline>
<Outline>
4.2: Calculate the change in mass number (A) for process S.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
4.1: Calculate change in Z: ΔZ = -3.
</Path>
<Path>
4.2: Calculate change in A: ΔA = -4.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
For process S, the atomic number decreases by 3 (ΔZ = -3), and the mass number decreases by 4 (ΔA = -4).
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
The mass number decreases by 4 (228 to 224) and atomic number decreases by 3 (91 to 88).
Let's figure that out.
First, if an alpha decay occurs, mass would decrease by 4 (so from 228 to 224), atomic number decreases by 2 (91 to 89).
To get from 89 to 88, need a decrease of 1.
That would be a beta plus decay, since that reduces the atomic number by 1.
Alternatively, electron capture, but beta plus is a possible emission.
So in this case, maybe one alpha and one beta plus.
Because starting from 91: after alpha, it's 89, and then beta plus (or electron capture) to 88.
Therefore, emitting one alpha and one beta plus.
So check List-II, that is option 1: one alpha and one beta plus.
So S would be 1.
Wait, maybe another way: If you had two alpha decays, but mass would decrease by 8.
Wait, but mass here decreases by 4.
So only one alpha decay.
So from 91 to 89 (after alpha), then how to decrease by 1 to 88.
Either beta plus decay or electron capture.
Since electron capture doesn't emit a positron, but actually involves capturing an electron and emitting a neutrino.
But beta plus decay does emit a positron.
Depending on whether beta plus is allowed.
Let me check if the decay from atomic number 89 (Actinium, maybe) to 88 (Radium) could occur via beta plus.
But electron capture is usually in higher atomic numbers, but if the nucleus is proton-rich, it can undergo beta plus decay.
But here, we're going from 89 to 88.
So, emitting a positron (beta plus) would decrease the atomic number by 1.
So that would require converting a proton into a neutron.
So that's a beta plus decay.
Therefore, total emissions: one alpha and one beta plus.
So that is option 1.
Hence, S matches with 1.
So to recap:
P: U to Pa, involves one alpha and one beta-minus (Option 4)
Q: Pb to Pb, involves one alpha and two beta-minus (Option 3)
R: Tl to Pb, one alpha and three beta-minus (Option 2)
S: Pa to Ra, one alpha and one beta-plus (Option 1)
</Path>
<Conclusion>
Process P (U-238 -> Pa-234, ΔZ=-1, ΔA=-4) involves emission of one alpha and one beta minus particle, matching List-II Option 4.
Process Q (Pb-214 -> Pb-210, ΔZ=0, ΔA=-4) involves emission of one alpha and two beta minus particles, matching List-II Option 3.
Process R (Tl-210 -> Pb-206, ΔZ=+1, ΔA=-4) involves emission of one alpha and three beta minus particles, matching List-II Option 2.
Process S (Pa-228 -> Ra-224, ΔZ=-3, ΔA=-4) involves emission of one alpha and one beta plus particle, matching List-II Option 1.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Looking at the answer options, which combination is this?
Let's check:
Option A: P→4, Q→3, R→2, S→1.
So that's exactly what I got.
Wait, check the options:
Options given are (A) through (D).
Let's look at option A: P→4, Q→3, R→2, S→1.
So that should be correct.
But let me check others to ensure.
Answer (A) is indeed the mapping I deduced.
But let me check each of them once again for correctness.
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Verification of the decay path and emitted particles for the transformation of Uranium-238 to Protactinium-234.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Verification of the decay path and emitted particles for the transformation of Lead-214 to Lead-210.
</Outline>
<Outline>
3: Verification of the decay path and emitted particles for the transformation of Thallium-210 to Lead-206.
</Outline>
<Outline>
4: Verification of the decay path and emitted particles for the transformation of Protactinium-228 to Radium-224.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Process P describes the transformation of Uranium-238 into Protactinium-234. This decay sequence involves an initial alpha emission followed by a beta minus decay. Uranium-238, with an atomic number of 92, first emits an alpha particle, transitioning to Thorium-234, which has an atomic number of 90 and a mass number of 234. Thorium-234 then undergoes beta minus decay, emitting an electron, to become Protactinium-234 with an atomic number of 91. This combined process correctly accounts for the changes, as the alpha decay reduces the atomic number by 2, and the beta minus decay increases it by 1, aligning with Protactinium's atomic number relative to the intermediate Thorium.
The complete decay chain from U-238 to Pa-234 results in the emission of one alpha particle and one beta minus particle.
This emission profile corresponds to option 4 in the provided list.
Therefore, the P→4 match is validated as correct.
</Path>
<Path>
2: Process Q details the transformation of Lead-214 to Lead-210. In this decay, the mass number decreases by 4, indicating the emission of one alpha particle, while the atomic number of Lead remains unchanged. An alpha particle emission inherently reduces the atomic number by 2. To counteract this reduction and preserve the original atomic number, two beta minus decays are necessary. Each beta minus decay increases the atomic number by 1, thereby achieving a net zero change in atomic number for the overall process.
The total particles emitted during this transformation are one alpha particle and two beta minus particles.
This specific combination of emitted particles aligns with option 3.
Consequently, the Q→3 assignment is verified as correct.
</Path>
<Path>
3: Process R describes the decay of Thallium-210 to Lead-206. The atomic number increases by 1 (from Thallium's 81 to Lead's 82), while the mass number decreases by 4, which signifies an alpha particle emission. The initial alpha decay from Thallium-210 (atomic number 81) would produce an intermediate nuclide with mass number 206 and atomic number 79. To reach the final product, Lead-206 (atomic number 82), the atomic number must increase by 3 from this intermediate state. This increase is accomplished through the emission of three beta minus particles.
The total particles emitted throughout this process are one alpha particle and three beta minus particles.
This combination corresponds to option 2.
</Path>
<Path>
4: Process S details the transformation of Protactinium-228 to Radium-224. The mass number decreases by 4 in this decay, indicating the emission of an alpha particle. When Protactinium-228 (atomic number 91) emits an alpha particle, it transforms into Actinium-224 (atomic number 89). To reach the final product, Radium-224 (atomic number 88), the atomic number must decrease by an additional unit from Actinium's 89. This further reduction in atomic number is achieved through a beta plus decay, involving the emission of a positron.
The total particles emitted during this sequence are one alpha particle and one beta plus particle.
This specific set of emissions matches option 1 from the list.
Therefore, the S→1 assignment is confirmed to be correct.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The re-verification confirms the following decay processes and their corresponding particle emissions: Process P (U-238 to Pa-234) emits one alpha and one beta minus particle, matching option 4. Process Q (Pb-214 to Pb-210) emits one alpha and two beta minus particles, matching option 3. Process R (Tl-210 to Pb-206) emits one alpha and three beta minus particles, matching option 2. Process S (Pa-228 to Ra-224) emits one alpha and one beta plus particle, matching option 1. All these determined matches are correct.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Therefore, (A) is the correct answer.
Looking at the options, option A states exactly this mapping.
Just to ensure that the other options are different.
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Determination of the validity of Option B's decay process matches based on radioactive decay principles.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Determination of the validity of Option C's decay process matches based on radioactive decay principles.
</Outline>
<Outline>
3: Determination of the validity of Option D's decay process matches based on radioactive decay principles.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Option B proposes specific decay mappings, including P→4, Q→1, R→2, and S→5. The match Q→1 signifies the emission of one alpha particle and one beta plus particle. For process Q, the transformation of Lead-214 to Lead-210, the atomic number must remain unchanged (ΔZ = 0). An alpha particle emission reduces the atomic number by 2, and a beta plus particle emission reduces it by 1. The combined effect of one alpha and one beta plus emission is a net decrease in atomic number by 3 (-2 + -1 = -3); this relies on the principle that beta plus decay decreases atomic number, while beta minus decay increases it.
The net change in atomic number (ΔZ) for the Q→1 scenario, resulting from one alpha emission (ΔZ_alpha = -2) and one beta plus emission (ΔZ_beta+ = -1), is calculated as -3.
The required change in atomic number for process Q is 0.
The proposed match Q→1 is inconsistent with the required ΔZ of 0 for process Q.
If Lead-214 (Z=82) were to emit one alpha and one beta plus particle, its atomic number would change from 82 to 79 (82 - 2 - 1 = 79), not remain 82 as required for the product Lead-210.
This calculated outcome of Z=79 does not match the observed transformation to Z=82.
Option B is incorrect.
</Path>
<Path>
2: Option C presents the mappings P→5, Q→3, R→1, and S→4. The match P→5 signifies the emission of one alpha particle and two beta plus particles. In the transformation of Uranium (Z=92) to Protactinium (Z=91) for process P, an alpha particle emission changes the atomic number by -2, and two beta plus particles each change it by -1, for a combined beta plus effect of -2. The total change in atomic number (ΔZ) from one alpha emission (ΔZ_alpha = -2) and two beta plus emissions (2 * ΔZ_beta+ = -2) is calculated as -2 + (-2) = -4. The actual decay of Uranium (Z=92) to Protactinium (Z=91) in process P involves a change in atomic number (ΔZ) of -1 (91 - 92).
The calculated ΔZ of -4 does not match the required ΔZ of -1 for process P.
Option C is incorrect.
</Path>
<Path>
3: Option D suggests the mappings P→5, Q→1, R→3, and S→2. This option includes previously invalidated matches: P→5 results in ΔZ = -4 instead of the required ΔZ = -1 for process P, and Q→1 results in ΔZ = -3 instead of the required ΔZ = 0 for process Q. The presence of these incorrect matches invalidates Option D.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
Option B's Q→1 match (one alpha, one beta+ emission) yields a ΔZ of -3; the Pb-214 to Pb-210 transformation requires ΔZ of 0, making Option B incorrect. Option C's P→5 match (one alpha, two beta+ emissions) results in a ΔZ of -4; the U-238 to Pa-234 decay requires a ΔZ of -1, rendering Option C incorrect. Option D includes the erroneous match Q→1 (ΔZ = -3 for a required ΔZ = 0) and P→5 (ΔZ = -4 for a required ΔZ = -1); these incorrect inclusions invalidate Option D.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Therefore, the correct answer must be (A).
</Think>