<Think>
Okay, let's try to figure out how to solve this weird calculator problem.
The first part asks for a sequence of exactly eight button presses starting from 1 to get to 313.
The buttons are D# (which doubles and adds 1) and Db (which doubles and subtracts 1).
Let me think through this step by step.
First, understanding the operations.
If I press D#, the number becomes 2x + 1.
If I press Db, it becomes 2x - 1.
So pressing either button doubles the current number and then either adds or subtracts 1.
The challenge is to find a sequence of eight such operations starting from 1 that results in 313.
Since it's asking for a sequence of eight presses, maybe we can model this as a binary tree where each node branches into two possibilities: D# or Db.
But since eight operations are needed, the tree depth would be eight.
However, 2^8 = 256 possible sequences, which is manageable for a computer but too tedious manually.
So we need a better strategy.
Alternatively, maybe we can work backwards.
If we start from 313 and reverse the operations.
Let's see: to reverse D# (which is 2x + 1), we would need to subtract 1 and then divide by 2.
Similarly, reversing Db (which is 2x - 1), we need to add 1 and then divide by 2.
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Definition of the reverse operation for D# (2x+1).
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Definition of the reverse operation for Db (2x-1).
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Reversing the D# operation, which transforms a number x to 2x + 1, involves subtracting 1 from the result and then dividing by 2.
</Path>
<Path>
2: Reversing the Db operation, which transforms a number x to 2x - 1, requires adding 1 to the result and then dividing by 2.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The reverse operation for D# (resulting in y) is (y-1)/2, and for Db (resulting in y) is (y+1)/2.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
But this reverse process also needs to result in an integer at each step, since the calculator only deals with whole numbers.
So let's try working backwards.
Let’s denote that if after reversing an operation we get an integer, then that's a possible predecessor.
So starting at 313:
Since in reverse, each operation is (x reversed from D# would be (x-1)/2 and reversed from Db would be (x+1)/2).
Let's see:
313 can be obtained either by:
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: The potential predecessor of 313 obtained by reversing the D# operation.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: The potential predecessor of 313 obtained by reversing the Db operation.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Reversing the D# operation for the value 313 involves subtracting 1 and dividing by 2, which yields (313 - 1) / 2 = 312 / 2 = 156.
</Path>
<Path>
2: Reversing the Db operation for the value 313 involves adding 1 and dividing by 2, resulting in (313 + 1) / 2 = 314 / 2 = 157.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The potential integer predecessors for the number 313 are 156, obtained by reversing the D# operation, and 157, obtained by reversing the Db operation.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
So the predecessors of 313 are 156 and 157.
Similarly, for each of those numbers, we can reverse the operations again until we reach 1 in eight steps.
So, step 1 (reverse order step 8):
Level 8 (original number): 313
Level 7: 156 or 157
Let’s track both possibilities.
First path: Let's try 156 first.
156.
Can 156 be obtained via reverse operations?
Yes, same idea:
From 156:
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: The potential predecessor of 156 using the reverse D# operation.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: The potential predecessor of 156 using the reverse Db operation.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: The reverse D# operation applied to 156 results in (156 - 1) / 2, which equals 155 / 2 or 77.5; this value is not an integer.
</Path>
<Path>
2: Applying the reverse Db operation to 156 yields (156 + 1) / 2, calculating to 157 / 2 or 78.5; this result is not an integer.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
Neither the reverse D# operation nor the reverse Db operation produces an integer predecessor when applied to the number 156.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Wait a second, that can't be.
If 156 is a predecessor, then when reversing, both possible previous values must be integers, but here neither is.
This must mean that 156 cannot be obtained from any previous number.
Wait, so maybe 313 cannot originate from 156?
Because to get 156 via forward operations, you would need to do a D# or Db on 77.5 or 78.5, which are not integers, so 156 must not have a valid predecessor.
Therefore, 156 is invalid?
Hmm.
But in reverse direction, 156 is a predecessor of 313, but if 156 itself doesn't have predecessors, then the path leading to 156 is invalid.
Therefore, the only possible valid predecessor of 313 is 157.
Check 157:
157 can come from
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: The potential predecessor of 157 resulting from reversing the D# operation.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: The potential predecessor of 157 resulting from reversing the Db operation.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Reversing the D# operation for 157 involves subtracting 1 and dividing by 2, which yields (157 - 1) / 2 = 156 / 2 = 78.
</Path>
<Path>
2: Reversing the Db operation for 157 requires adding 1 and dividing by 2, resulting in (157 + 1) / 2 = 158 / 2 = 79.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
Reversing the operations from 157 yields potential integer predecessors of 78 (from D#) and 79 (from Db).
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
So predecessors of 157 are 78 and 79.
Level 6:
So either 78 or 79.
Let’s check both.
Starting with 78.
78 can come from
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Determine the result of applying the reverse D# operation to 78.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Determine the result of applying the reverse Db operation to 78.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Applying the reverse D# operation to 78 yields (78 - 1) / 2 = 77 / 2 = 38.5, which is not an integer.
</Path>
<Path>
2: Applying the reverse Db operation to 78 yields (78 + 1) / 2 = 79 / 2 = 39.5, which is not an integer.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
Neither the reverse D# nor the reverse Db operation produces an integer when applied to 78.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
So 78 is invalid.
Thus, must take the other predecessor, 79.
79:
(79 can come from)
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: The potential predecessor of 79 obtained by reversing the D# operation.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: The potential predecessor of 79 obtained by reversing the Db operation.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Reversing the D# operation for 79 involves subtracting 1 and dividing by 2, yielding (79 - 1) / 2 = 78 / 2 = 39.
</Path>
<Path>
2: Reversing the Db operation for 79 involves adding 1 and dividing by 2, resulting in (79 + 1) / 2 = 80 / 2 = 40.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
Reversing the operations from 79 yields potential integer predecessors of 39 (from D#) and 40 (from Db).
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
So 79 can come from 39 or 40.
Level 5: 39 or 40
Check both.
Start with 39. (Original reasoning text reordered here - checks 39 first, then 40. Outline checks 40 first. Following original text order.)
Predecessors for 39:
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Potential predecessor of 39 via reverse D# operation.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Potential predecessor of 39 via reverse Db operation.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Reversing the D# operation for the value 39 yields (39 - 1) / 2, which simplifies to 38 / 2, resulting in the integer 19.
</Path>
<Path>
2: Reversing the Db operation for the value 39 yields (39 + 1) / 2, which simplifies to 40 / 2, resulting in the integer 20.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
Reversing the operations from 39 yields two potential integer predecessors: 19 (from D#) and 20 (from Db).
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
So 39 can come from 19 or 20.
Then 40.
Predecessors for 40:
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Check if 40 has an integer predecessor by applying the reverse D# operation.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Check if 40 has an integer predecessor by applying the reverse Db operation.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Applying the reverse D# operation to 40 gives (40 -1)/2 = 39/2 = 19.5, which is not an integer.
</Path>
<Path>
2: Applying the reverse Db operation to 40 gives (40 + 1)/2 = 41 /2 = 20.5, which is not an integer.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
Reversing either the D# or Db operation from 40 does not yield an integer result.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Thus, only predecessors for 40 do not exist.
Therefore, 40 isn't a valid predecessor, so 79 came from 39.
Wait, how did we get here?
Wait: 79 is at Level 5, obtained from Step 6 (reverse step 3).
To get 79 at level 5, in forward steps:
Starting from Level 5's number, we did a button press to get to Level 6 (79 to 157? Wait, maybe we need to clarify the steps.
Hold on, perhaps getting confused.
Original Problem: When we work backwards, each reverse step is undoing one button press.
So starting from 313 (which is the result after eight presses).
To reverse a press, we have:
If last press was D#, then previous number was (313 -1)/2 = 156
If last press was Db, then previous number was (313 + 1)/2 = 157
But since 156 can't be reversed (needs previous to be non-integers), therefore last press must have been Db, resulting in 157.
So we now have 157 after seven presses.
Then for seven presses, we have 157.
Now working backwards: to get to six presses:
If seventh press was D#, then previous number was (157 -1)/2 = 156 / 2 = 78.
If seventh press was Db, previous number was (157 + 1)/2 = 158 /2 = 79.
So predecessors are 78 and 79.
But 78 can't be reversed further, as before.
So again, seems that only 79 is possible.
Wait, but is that correct?
Wait, the 157 after seven presses comes from either 78 via D# or 79 via Db.
If the seventh press was D#, then predecessor is 78.
Otherwise, predecessor is 79.
But upon reversing, at that step (seven presses in), can 78 or 79 be there.
So predecessors at step 7 would be 78 or 79, but as in previous steps, but to check if they can be obtained.
Wait, perhaps instead of this, let me approach this step by step:
Starting from 313 (step 8):
Possible predecessors:
If last move was D#: previous number = (313 - 1)/2 = 312/2 = 156
If last move was Db: previous number = (313 + 1)/2 = 314/2 = 157
Check if 156 can lead to earlier steps.
As above, when we tried to reverse 156, neither predecessor give integers, so 156 is invalid.
Thus, last move must have been Db, resulting in predecessor 157 at step 7.
Step 7: 157
Possible predecessors: via D#: (157 -1)/2 = 156 /2 = 78
Via Db: (157 +1)/2 = 158 /2 =79
Check step 6:
Case 1: Step 6 was 78 via D#
But reversing 78: predecessors via D# would be (78 -1)/2 =77.5, non-integer.
Similarly via Db: 79.5 non-integer.
So 78 invalid.
Thus, step 6 must have been 79 via Db.
Step 6: 79
Now predecessors: via D#: (79 -1)/2 =78/2 = 39; via Db: (79 +1)/2 =80/2=40.
So predecessors: 39 or 40.
Check step 5:
a. Step 5 could be 39 via D#: then step 5 was 39.
If we take 39:
Predecessors via D#: (39 -1)/2 =38/2=19; via Db: (39 +1)/2=40/2=20.
So predecessors: 19 or 20. Both integers, so valid.
b. Step 5 could be 40 via Db: (79 came from 40 Db).
Then predecessors for 40 would be: via D#: (40 -1)/2=39/2=19.5, non-integer; via Db: (40 +1)/2=41/2=20.5, non-integer.
So since 40 can't be obtained from previous operations, Step 5 must have been 39.
Thus, step 5: 39
Predecessors: via D# gives 19 or via Db gives 20.
Check step 4:
Need to check both possibilities.
If step 4 was 19 (from D# on step4 number):
predecessors of 19:
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: The potential predecessor of 19 via the reversed D# operation.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: The potential predecessor of 19 via the reversed Db operation.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Reversing the D# operation for the value 19 involves subtracting 1 and dividing by 2, resulting in (19 - 1) / 2 = 18 / 2 = 9.
</Path>
<Path>
2: Reversing the Db operation for the value 19 involves adding 1 and dividing by 2, resulting in (19 + 1) / 2 = 20 / 2 = 10.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
Reversing the D# operation yields 9 as a potential predecessor for 19, while reversing the Db operation yields 10.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Both valid.
If step 4 was 20 (from Db on step4 number):
predecessors of 20:
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: The result of applying the reverse D# operation to 20 to check for an integer predecessor.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: The result of applying the reverse Db operation to 20 to check for an integer predecessor.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Applying the reverse D# operation to 20 yields (20 - 1) / 2, which calculates to 19 / 2 or 9.5.
</Path>
<Path>
2: Applying the reverse Db operation to 20 yields (20 + 1) / 2, which calculates to 21 / 2 or 10.5; this result indicates an invalid predecessor.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
Neither reversing the D# operation nor reversing the Db operation from the number 20 results in an integer.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
So predecessors for 20 are non-integer. Therefore, 20 can't be.
Therefore, step4 must have come from 19.
So step5 was 39 from D# on 19, so step4 is 19.
Step4:19
predecessors:
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: The potential predecessor of 19 resulting from reversing the D# operation.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: The potential predecessor of 19 resulting from reversing the Db operation.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Reversing the D# operation from the value 19 yields the predecessor (19-1)/2, which is 9.
</Path>
<Path>
2: Reversing the Db operation from the value 19 yields the predecessor (19+1)/2, which is 10.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The potential predecessors for the number 19 are 9, resulting from reversing a D# operation, and 10, resulting from reversing a Db operation.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Step3:
Either.
So to step3, possible 9 or 10.
Check both:
If took 9:
predecessors (for 9):
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: The potential predecessor of 9 obtained by reversing the D# operation.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: The potential predecessor of 9 obtained by reversing the Db operation.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Reversing the D# operation for the number 9 yields (9 - 1) / 2, which simplifies to 8 / 2, resulting in the integer 4.
</Path>
<Path>
2: Reversing the Db operation for the number 9 yields (9 + 1) / 2, which simplifies to 10 / 2, resulting in the integer 5.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
Reversing the operations from 9 yields two potential integer predecessors: 4 (from D#) and 5 (from Db).
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
If took10:
predecessors (for 10):
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Determine the potential predecessor of 10 using the reverse D# operation.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Determine the potential predecessor of 10 using the reverse Db operation.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Applying the reverse D# operation to 10 yields (10 - 1) / 2 = 9.5, which is not an integer.
</Path>
<Path>
2: Applying the reverse Db operation to 10 yields (10 + 1) / 2 = 10.5, which is not an integer.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
Neither the reverse D# operation nor the reverse Db operation applied to 10 produces an integer predecessor.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
So only 9 can lead to 10 via step3. (This sentence seems confused, refers to forward from 9 to 10? It should be backward from 19 to 9, as 10 is invalid). Let's interpret it as "So only 9 is a valid predecessor for 19, as 10 is invalid" which follows from the previous conclusion.
Wait: step4 is 19.
It comes from step3 doing D# or Db.
Wait, if step3 ends with number x, then step4 is either 2x +1 (if D#) or 2x -1 (if Db).
To get 19, which is step4, we can have step3's number as:
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: The predecessor value when 19 is reached using the D# operation.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: The predecessor value when 19 is reached using the Db operation.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Reversing the D# operation from 19 yields a predecessor value calculated as (19 - 1) / 2, which equals 9.
</Path>
<Path>
2: Reversing the Db operation from 19 yields a predecessor value calculated as (19 + 1) / 2, which equals 10.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
Reversing the operations from 19 indicates that the preceding number could be 9 (if D# was the last operation) or 10 (if Db was the last operation).
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
But 10 predecessors aren't valid.
Therefore step3 is 9.
So step3:9.
predecessors:
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: The potential predecessor of 9 obtained by reversing the D# operation.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: The potential predecessor of 9 obtained by reversing the Db operation.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Reversing the D# operation for the number 9 yields the predecessor 4.
</Path>
<Path>
2: Reversing the Db operation for the number 9 yields the predecessor 5.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
Reversing the operations from 9 yields potential predecessors of 4 (from D#) and 5 (from Db).
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Step2:
case1:4 arrived from predecessor.
But step3=9 need step2's number?
If step2=4, then pressing D# would give 9 = 2*4 +1=9.
So press D#.
Or if step2=5, pressing Db gives 2*5 -1=9.
Wait, this may be getting complex.
Wait: starting from step 0 (1), so step 1 after first press, step 8 is 313.
Working backwards, step8 is 313, step7 is 157, step6 is 79, step5 is 39, step4 is19, step3 is9, step2 is4 or5 from predecessors.
Wait:
Trace:
8:313 (from step7:157 via Db)
7:157 (from step6:79 via Db)
6:79 (from step5:39 via D#)
5:39 (from step4:19 via D#)
4:19 (from step3:9 via D#)
3:9 (from step2:4 via D# or 5 via Db?)
Wait step3 is 9, which can be obtained
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Determine if the number 9 can be generated from the number 4 using either the D# or Db operation.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Determine if the number 9 can be generated from the number 5 using either the D# or Db operation.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Applying the D# operation to the number 4 results in 2*4 + 1, which calculates to 9.
</Path>
<Path>
2: Applying the Db operation to the number 5 results in 2*5 - 1, which calculates to 9.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The number 9 can be reached by applying the D# operation to 4, and it can also be reached by applying the Db operation to 5.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
So step2 could be 4 or5.
So to have step3=9, predecessors could be 4 (if D# pressed) or5 (if Db pressed).
Both are valid.
Let me check.
First path: let's assume step2 is4.
step2:4
predecessors: (to get 4): if step2 is4, then if it came via D# from (4-1)/2=1.5→invalid, or via Db from (4 +1)/2=2.5→invalid.
So 4 can’t be obtained—it can't be.
Wait, no.
Wait, reverse.
If step2 is4, that means originally, starting from step0=1, after two presses, it's4.
Let’s check the forward operations.
Starting from1:
Perform forward calculation, conclude 4 is unreachable in 2 steps.
After first button press (either D# or Db). If D#:3, if Db:1.
After second button press:
If first Db, then second press can be D#: 2*1 +1=3 or Db:1 again.
If first D#, then second press: 2*3 +1=7 or 2*3 -1=5.
Thus after two presses, possible numbers are1,3,5,7.
Thus, number4 cannot be obtained in two presses.
Therefore, step2 cannot be4.
Hmm.
That conflicts with the reverse process.
So in reverse process, we think step2 was4, but forward process shows that 4 is unreachable in two steps.
Therefore, there's inconsistency here.
Therefore, the error is that in reverse process, we can get predecessors but they might not actually be reachable in forward steps.
Therefore, working backwards might lead us through paths that are impossible in forward steps.
This is getting interesting.
So need to be careful with the reverse method because even if mathematically the predecessors are integers, they might not correspond to feasible forward sequences.
Therefore, how do we resolve this?
So when reversing, perhaps sometimes multiple predecessors are possible, but only certain ones are reachable in forward direction.
Thus, instead, perhaps the reverse method can still work, but need to check in each step whether predecessors are actually reachable.
Wait, but this might complicate things.
Alternatively, instead, maybe try forward computation.
But since the problem needs finding a sequence of 8 steps starting at1, leading to313, forward calculation is possible but might need a lot of states.
However, maybe with some pruning, since the numbers can become large.
Let me see:
Each operation is of the form 2x ±1, so starting from1:
After 1 press: 3 or1
After2: 7,5 (from3)/1 (from1)
Wait that might be difficult.
Alternatively, 313 is large—it might need operations that compound growth.
Since each operation doubles, we can estimate the maximum possible number is 2^8 + some offsets.
Let's compute:
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Calculate the maximum possible value after 8 presses starting from 1, assuming D# is pressed every time.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Calculate the minimum possible value after 8 presses starting from 1, assuming Db is pressed every time.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Maximum possible number after 8 D# presses: each D# doubles and adds1.
This is similar to the recurrence a_n = 2a_{n-1} +1, starting from1.
Let’s compute the max possible:
a1=2*1 +1=3
a2=2*3 +1=7
a3=2*7 +1=15
a4=31
a5=63
a6=127
a7=255
a8=511
</Path>
<Path>
2: Similarly, minimum possible number (all Db presses) would be 2^n -1, here 1,1,1,1...?
Wait no, starting from1:
If press Db once:2*1 -1=1
Press again:2*1 -1=1.
So if pressed Db each time, it stays at1.
Wait, no, only if starting at1.
That might be a problem.
Wait, initial value is1.
Press Db once:2*1 -1=1
Press Db again: same.
So the minimum number after any number of presses is1, but maximum with all D#’s is 511.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The maximum value achievable in 8 steps is 511 (all D# presses). The minimum value achievable is 1 (all Db presses, or any sequence ending in Db from 1).
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
So 313 is between 255 and511, so even if not all D#s, likely majority are D#s.
But this is the problem.
Alternatively, since the number 313 is odd.
Looking at the operations: starting from1.
Let's observe that D# (double and add1) and Db (double and subtract1).
Each operation can be considered as:
If x is the current number, D# leads to 2x +1, Db leads to 2x -1.
So sequences of operations can be thought of as building a binary number, where each bit is either +1 or -1, scaled by powers of2.
Wait maybe express 313 in terms of powers of2 with modifications.
Let me see.
Let’s note that each operation adds or subtracts 1 after doubling.
So if we have operations o1, o2, ..., o8, each is ±1.
Then the final number can be written as:
Starting with1,
After first operation:2*1 + o1
Second operation:2*(2*1 + o1) + o2 =2^2*1 +2*o1 + o2
Third operation:2*(2^2*1 +2*o1 + o2) + o3=2^3*1 +2^2*o1 +2*o2 + o3
...
After eight operations:2^8*1 +2^7*o1 +2^6*o2 +...+2^0*o8
=256 +128*o1 +64*o2 +32*o3 +16*o4 +8*o5 +4*o6 +2*o7 +1*o8
Each oi is either +1 or -1.
Therefore, 256 + sum_{k=0}^{7} (2^{(7 -k)} * o_{k+1}) (This formula seems slightly off based on derivation S26.4)
Wait, more precisely:
Let me index o1 to o8 as first to eighth operations.
But in the expression above :
It's 2^8*1 +2^7*o1 +2^6*o2 +... +2^0*o8.
So 256 + (128*o1 +64*o2 +32*o3 +16*o4 +8*o5 +4*o6 +2*o7 +1*o8)
Therefore, our equation is:
256 + 128*o1 +64*o2 +32*o3 +16*o4 +8*o5 +4*o6 +2*o7 +1*o8 =313
Therefore, this simplifies to:
128*o1 +64*o2 +32*o3 +16*o4 +8*o5 +4*o6 +2*o7 +1*o8 =313 -256=57
Thus, need that sum =57 where each oi is ±1.
Let’s write that equation.
Each term 128*o1 down to 1*o8.
Hmm, so need to pick a combination of terms multiplying by 1 or -1, such that their sum is57.
But note that 128 is larger than57, so the coefficient of o1 cannot be -1 (since then we have -128 and then adding the rest.
remaining terms max is64 +32 +16 +8 +4 +2 +1=127.
So -128 +127= -1, which is not sufficient to reach57.
Therefore, o1 must be +1, contributing128.
Then the remaining sum from other terms is57 -128= -71.
Therefore, we need sum from o2 to o8:
64*o2 +32*o3 +16*o4 +8*o5 +4*o6 +2*o7 +1*o8= -71.
But 64+32+16+8+4+2+1=127.
If all o's were +1, sum would be127.
But we need sum =-71.
That's like flipping enough signs to reduce the total by 198 (since 127 -2*198=127-396=-269 which is not. Wait. Wait,
The sum S is = sum(64*o2 +... +1*o8).
If all o are +1, S=127.
To get S=-71, which is difference of 127 - (-71)=198.
To flip a term oi from +1 to -1, we subtract 2*value of that term.
So need cumulative subtraction from flipping to be 127 - (-71)=198.
Therefore, the total amount need to be subtracted via flips:198.
Each flip of a term with coefficient c decreases the total by 2c.
Therefore, we need to find a subset of {64,32,16,8,4,2,1} such that twice their sum equals198.
Wait 198/2=99.
Therefore, is there a subset of these terms that sum to99.
Hmm. Let me check.
The terms available are64,32,16,8,4,2,1.
Need sum 99.
99 in binary is64 +32 + 2 +1.
64 +32=96.
99-96=3, which is2 +1.
So yes. 64,32,2,1 sum to99.
Therefore, flip these four terms.
So o2= -1, o3= -1, o7= -1, o8= -1.
Wait, but the coefficients are64=o2,32=o3,16=o4,8=o5,4=o6,2=o7,1=o8.
Wait no:
The terms to flip are the ones contributing to subtract 2*(64 +32+2+1)=2*99=198.
Therefore, if we flip o2 (-64 instead +64), o3 (-32 instead +32), o7 (-2 instead +2), and o8 (-1 instead +1)), our total sum S=127 - 2*(64 +32 + 2 +1)=127 -198= -71.
Therefore, this indeed.
Thus, constructing the sequence:
o1=+1 (D#)
o2=-1 (Db)
o3=-1 (Db)
o4=+1 (D#)
o5=+1 (D#)
o6=+1 (D#)
o7=-1 (Db)
o8=-1 (Db)
Thus, the sequence is [D#, Db, Db, D#, D#, D#, Db, Db].
Let me verify:
Start with1.
Press1: D#: 2*1 +1=3
Press2: Db:2*3 -1=5
Press3: Db:2*5 -1=9
Press4: D#:2*9 +1=19
Press5: D#:2*19 +1=39
Press6: D#:2*39 +1=79
Press7: Db:2*79 -1=157
Press8: Db:2*157 -1=313
Yes, that works.
So the sequence is D#, Db, Db, D#, D#, D#, Db, Db.
That gives exactly 313.
So part (i) is answered.
For part (ii), asking to describe all numbers achievable in exactly eight presses starting from1.
Need to show all possible numbers and that no others.
Given each of the eight presses is either +1 or -1 after doubling, as per the previous problem.
As analyzed in part (i), the number obtained is of the form N=2^8 + sum_{k=1}^8 o_k *2^{8 -k} where o_k is ±1. (Using the formula from S26.9/S26.10 derived in the text)
But more accurately, N=2^8 + sum_{k=1}^8 o_k *2^{8 -k} (since 1 at the start, follow the recursive 2x ±1). (Seems repetitive of S36)
Expanding, this gives:
N = 256 + 128 o1 + 64 o2 +32 o3 +16 o4 +8 o5 +4 o6 +2 o7 +1 o8
Thus, each coefficient o1 to o8 is ±1.
So each term contributes ± the corresponding power of two, then added to 256.
Therefore, the possible numbers N can be written as:
N =256 + Σ_{i=0}^7 ( ±2^i )
Wait, if we reverse the order, terms for o1 corresponds to 2^7, o2 correspond to 2^6,..., o8 corresponds to 2^0. (This refers to the summation, which aligns with S36.3 where o1 multiplies 128=2^7, ..., o8 multiplies 1=2^0)
So we can reindex terms:
N=256 + o1*2^7 + o2*2^6 + ... + o8*2^0, where each oi ∈ {-1, +1} (This is the same as S36.3)
So, so each coefficient is ±1 times 128, 64,...,1, and all those are added to 256.
Therefore, the possible values of N are all numbers from256 - (128 +64 +32 +16 +8 +4 +2 +1) to256 + (128 +64 +32 +16 +8 +4 +2 +1).
Let's compute those.
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: The sum of powers of 2 from 2^0 to 2^7.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: The maximum value of the summation term Σ o_k * 2^(8-k).
</Outline>
<Outline>
3: The minimum value of the summation term Σ o_k * 2^(8-k).
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: The sum of the powers of 2 from 2^0 to 2^7 (1 + 2 + 4 + 8 + 16 + 32 + 64 + 128) is 255.
</Path>
<Path>
2: The maximum possible value for the summation term occurs when all coefficients o_k are +1, resulting in a sum of 255.
</Path>
<Path>
3: The minimum possible value for the summation term occurs when all coefficients o_k are -1, resulting in a sum of -255.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The value of the summation term Σ o_k * 2^(8-k) lies within the range [-255, 255].
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Therefore, N can range from256 -255=1 to256 +255=511. (Mapped from S37.2 in original text)
But not every integer in1 to511 is achievable. (Mapped from S37.3 in original text)
In particular, depending on coefficients, each oi allows for adding or subtracting 2^{7 - i+1} (i from1 to8), so adjusted per each bit. (Mapped from S37.4 in original text)
Wait, but since it's the sum of eight terms each ±2^{k} for k=0 to7, then total delta is Σ_{k=0}^{7} ±2^{k}, and this sum can range from-255 to+255 (since sum of 2^0 +2^1 +...+2^7=2^8-1=255). (Mapped from S37.5 in original text)
Therefore, the total sum added to256 can go from256 -255=1 to256 +255=511.
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Calculate the minimum possible value of N using the minimum summation value.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Calculate the maximum possible value of N using the maximum summation value.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Minimum N = 256 - 255 = 1.
</Path>
<Path>
2: Maximum N = 256 + 255 = 511.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The achievable number N must be within the range [1, 511].
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Moreover, notice that each delta term can make increments or decrements by even numbers? (Mapped from S38.1 in original text)
No, because the terms are 1,2,4,...,128, which are up to128. (Mapped from S38.2 in original text)
The sum has a parity same as the number of ±1, because the other terms are even: 2,4,...,128—all even. (Mapped from S38.3 in original text)
Thus, the parity of the sum Σ_{k=0}^{7} ±2^k is equal to the parity of the term with 1 (since 1 is only odd term; other terms are even). (Mapped from S38.4 in original text)
Thus, if the coefficient of1 (i.e., o8) is +1 or -1, the sum overall will be congruent to1 mod2 or -1 mod2, but -1 mod2 is equivalent to1 mod2. (Mapped from S38.5 in original text)
Wait, no. (Mapped from S38.6 in original text)
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Determine the parity of the final number N by analyzing the parity of the summation term in the formula N = 256 + sum.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Determine the parity of the final number N by analyzing how the parity changes with each D# or Db operation starting from 1.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Analyze N = 256 + sum, show sum is odd, conclude N=odd.
Wait, no: coefficient of1 is o8 which is ±1.
Thus the total sum Σ_{k=0}^{7} ±2^k is equivalent to o8 mod2.
Therefore, the total delta, which is Σ ±2^k, is either even or odd based on o8.
Hence, adding that to256, the parity of N is as follows:
256 is even.
Then, if delta is of delta=even + even +...+ terms.
Wait but:
Wait, delta= Σ_{k=0}^{7} ±2^k.
Notice that except for the term 2^0=1, all other terms are even.
Therefore, the delta is ±1 plus even numbers.
Therefore, delta is odd.
Therefore, N=256 + delta (odd) is even + odd=odd.
Therefore, all possible numbers N achievable are odd numbers from1 to511.
Wait, but earlier I saw that the range should be1 to511.
If N=256 ± delta, delta up to255.
But delta itself is from-255 to255, so N=256 +delta, so 256-255=1 to256 +255=511.
Wait, butN can only be odd since delta is odd (sum of coefficients including ±1 (term1)).
So N must be odd.
Therefore, the set of numbers is all odd numbers between1 and511 inclusive.
Wait, let me confirm:
</Path>
<Path>
2: Prove oddness by induction on operations.
First, starting from1, the parity after each button press.
Operations are double +1 or double -1.
Let's track the parity:
Start with1 (odd).
Each operation:
If current number is even, then:
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
2.1: Determine the parity after applying D# to an even number.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2.2: Determine the parity after applying Db to an even number.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
2.1: Even *2 +1= odd
</Path>
<Path>
2.2: Even*2 -1=odd
</Path>
<Conclusion>
Applying either D# or Db to an even number results in an odd number.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
If current number is odd:
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
2.1: Determine the parity after applying D# to an odd number.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2.2: Determine the parity after applying Db to an odd number.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
2.1: Odd*2 +1= even +1=odd
</Path>
<Path>
2.2: Odd*2 -1=even -1=odd
</Path>
<Conclusion>
Applying either D# or Db to an odd number results in an odd number.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Wait: no: odd*2 is even.
So pressing either D# or Db on an odd number:
For example, if current is odd:
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
2.1: Show that applying D# to an odd number results in an odd number.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2.2: Show that applying Db to an odd number results in an odd number.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
2.1: D#: even +1= odd
</Path>
<Path>
2.2: Db: even -1= odd
</Path>
<Conclusion>
Applying either D# or Db to an odd number preserves oddness.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Wait, so starting from1 (odd), after any button press, you get odd again.
Wait that's a key insight.
Similarly, if starting at1 (odd):
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
2.1: Check the result of the first press being D#.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2.2: Check the result of the first press being Db.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
2.1: First Press: 2*1 +1=3 (odd) if D#
</Path>
<Path>
2.2: Or 2*1 -1=1 (odd) if Db
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The first press always results in an odd number (3 or 1).
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Thus, regardless of first press, the result is odd.
Similarly, each operation on an odd number gives another odd number.
Therefore, regardless of how many times you press the buttons, starting from1, all resulting numbers are odd.
So even numbers cannot be achieved.
But previously, reverse process suggested numbers like4 in reverse, but that's invalid because even numbers can't result.
Hence, the set of all possible numbers after eight presses is all odd numbers between1 and511 inclusive.
But let's verify this.
Another approach: since in each step pressing a button converts the number into 2x ±1, which preserves oddness.
Hence all numbers reachable are odd.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
Both methods show that any number N achievable in 8 steps starting from 1 must be odd. The formula N = 256 + sum shows the sum term is always odd, making N odd. The step-by-step analysis shows that starting with 1 (odd), each operation (2x+1 or 2x-1) preserves oddness.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Moreover, the maximum is511 as per prior calculations (all upper presses, hitting 2x+1 each time).
Yes.
So maximum8 D#=511.
Minimum is1 (if press Db eight times).
Wait but even in other combinations:
Wait pressing Db eight times gives:
Start1.
PressDb: remain1.
So pressing Db eight times would still be1.
But pressing D# once and Db seven times:
For example, alternated with multiple steps.
So you can check.
But no matter how you press, the numbers stay odd.
So regardless, starting from odd, staying odd.
So after eight presses, result is odd.
Furthermore, the maximum after eight D#'s is computed as3,7,15,31,63,127,255,511.
Yes.
So maximum8 D#=511.
Minimum would be1.
Because the first Db press will stay at1, and any subsequent Db press still keep at1.
But if you mix some Db's and D#'s, you can create varied paths.
For example, even though some paths may lead back to1, but others can generate numbers in between.
However, the key point here is that the numbers achievable must all be odd, from1 to511.
Wait, but in the first part, we reached313 which is odd.
So then, all numbers in [1,511] with odd parity can be achieved?
Wait, but can all odd numbers in1 to511 be achieved?
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: The comparison between the count of possible 8-step sequences and the count of odd integers in the [1, 511] range.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: The uniqueness (injectivity) of the mapping from an 8-step sequence to the resulting number N.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: A comparison is made between the 256 possible sequences and the 256 target odd integers. If each of the 256 distinct eight-press sequences leads to a unique number, and all 256 target numbers are reachable, then these sequences and numbers would form a bijection; however, the existence of such a bijection must be formally established.
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1.1: The total number of distinct 8-step sequences.
</Outline>
<Outline>
1.2: The total count of odd integers within the inclusive range of 1 to 511.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1.1: The number of possible 8-step sequences is 2^8, which equals 256; this corresponds to the count of odd numbers between 1 and 511.
</Path>
<Path>
1.2: The count of odd integers from 1 to 511 inclusive, with a step of 2, is calculated as (511 - 1)/2 + 1, which simplifies to 255 + 1, resulting in 256 numbers. This confirms there are exactly 256 such odd integers.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
A total of 256 distinct 8-step sequences exist, and there are 256 odd integers in the range [1, 511].
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
</Path>
<Path>
2: The injectivity of the mapping from a sequence of operations to the resulting number N is considered. An injective relationship means that distinct sequences produce distinct numbers. The resulting number N is formulated as N = 256 + Σ_{k=1}^8 o_k * 2^(8-k), where each o_k is either -1 or +1. This formulation can be rephrased to isolate the sum: Σ_{k=1}^8 o_k * 2^(8-k) = N - 256.
Consequently, each specific sequence of operations (o1, ..., o8) corresponds to a unique integer value for the term (N - 256).
The representation of (N - 256) as a sum where terms are powers of 2 multiplied by ±1 suggests uniqueness, as each such sum effectively forms a number with digits from {-1, 1}, analogous to a signed binary representation.
This system shows similarities to a balanced ternary system, adapted for a binary base.
Each distinct combination of coefficients (o_k values) yields a unique sum.
It is necessary to verify if every integer within the range [-255, 255] can be formed by such a sum, which would imply that N (equal to 256 + sum) ranges from 1 to 511, with each N being an odd number.
The number N is determined by 256 plus this sum, which itself ranges from -255 to +255.
Therefore, the minimum possible value for N is 256 - 255 = 1, and the maximum is 256 + 255 = 511.
The achievable numbers N are precisely those for which N - 256 can be expressed as the sum Σ o_k * 2^(8-k).
Each distinct combination of o1 through o8 leads to a unique value of N, and there are 2^8 = 256 such distinct combinations.
The target set consists of 256 odd numbers (from 1 to 511), matching the number of unique combinations, which suggests a bijective mapping.
Consequently, every odd number between 1 and 511 inclusive can be achieved by a specific sequence of eight button presses.
The ability to find a sequence for 313, along with the established maximum of 511 and minimum of 1, and the nature of incremental button presses, supports this range.
The formula N = 2^8 + Σ_{k=1}^8 o_k * 2^(8-k) shows that since the sum term (Σ o_k * 2^(8-k)) ranges from -Σ(2^i) to +Σ(2^i) for i=0 to 7 (i.e., -255 to +255), N itself ranges from 1 to 511.
Only odd numbers are reachable because N is the sum of 2^8 (which is 256, an even number) and the sum term.
This sum term, denoted as delta, is composed of 128*o1 + 64*o2 + ... + 1*o8.
All components of delta (128*o1, 64*o2, ..., 2*o7) are even, except for the last component (1*o8).
Therefore, delta can be represented as an even number plus 1*o8, meaning the parity of delta is determined by the parity of o8.
As o8 can only be +1 or -1, both of which are odd, o8 is always odd.
Consequently, delta is the sum of an even part and an odd part (o8), making delta itself odd.
Thus, the sum term delta is always odd.
The final number N, being 256 (even) + delta (odd), is therefore always odd.
This confirms that all achievable numbers N must be odd.
The minimum value for delta is -255 (when all o_k are -1), resulting in N = 256 - 255 = 1.
The maximum value for delta is +255 (when all o_k are +1), resulting in N = 256 + 255 = 511.
This range confirms that all odd numbers from 1 to 511 inclusive are indeed achievable.
The mapping from sequences to numbers is unique because each distinct sequence (o1, ..., o8) generates a unique sum.
To demonstrate this uniqueness, assume two different sequences, (o_k) and (o'_k), produce the same sum.
This assumption means Σ_{k=1}^8 o_k * 2^(8-k) = Σ_{k=1}^8 o'_k * 2^(8-k).
Subtracting these two sums yields Σ_{k=1}^8 (o_k - o'_k) * 2^(8-k) = 0.
The term (o_k - o'_k) can only take values of -2, 0, or +2, as o_k and o'_k are from {-1, +1}.
Let j be the first index (from 1 to 8) where o_j ≠ o'_j.
The term at this position j, (o_j - o'_j) * 2^(8-j), contributes ±2 * 2^(8-j) to the sum. The maximum possible absolute sum of all subsequent terms is Σ_{k=j+1}^8 |(o_k - o'_k) * 2^(8-k)|, which is at most Σ_{k=j+1}^8 2 * 2^(8-k) = 2 * (2^(8-j) - 1).
The sum of the magnitudes of subsequent terms, 2 * (2^(8-j) - 1), is strictly less than the magnitude of the first differing term, |±2 * 2^(8-j)| = 2 * 2^(8-j). Therefore, the non-zero contribution from the first differing term cannot be cancelled out by the sum of the subsequent terms.
This implies that no two distinct sequences (o_k) can produce the same sum.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The count of 256 possible 8-step sequences matches the 256 odd integers available in the target range [1, 511]. The mapping from any given sequence of operations to its corresponding final sum component, Σ o_k * 2^(8-k), is injective; this means each distinct sequence generates a unique sum and consequently a unique final number N.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Conclude bijection between sequences and odd integers [1, 511].
Therefore, the mapping is injective.
Since there are2^8=256 sequences and256 target numbers (1 to511 odds), hence it's bijective.
Injectivity + equal finite set sizes implies bijection. (Added based on reasoning)
Therefore every odd number [1,511] is achievable. (Added based on reasoning)
State final answer for part (ii): All odd integers from 1 to 511 inclusive.
Therefore, part (ii)'s answer is that all odd integers from1 to511 inclusive can be obtained by exactly eight button presses, and no others.
The argument is based on the fact that each press preserves oddness, the injective map between sequences and results, and the numbering range.
</Think>