<Think>
We have the additive group Z2, which means we're dealing with pairs of integers where the group operation is component-wise addition.
The subgroup H is the smallest subgroup containing the three elements (3,8), (4,-1), and (5,4).
We need to find a pair (x, y) with x > 0 such that H is equal to H_{xy}, the smallest subgroup generated by (0, x) and (1, y).
So, essentially, H_{xy} is the set of all integer linear combinations of (0, x) and (1, y).
That is, every element in H_{xy} can be written as a*(0, x) + b*(1, y) for some integers a and b.
Expanding that, each element in H_{xy} is of the form (b, a*x + b*y).
Our goal is to find x and y such that the subgroup generated by (3,8), (4,-1), and (5,4) is the same as the subgroup generated by (0, x) and (1, y).
And we need x to be positive.
First, let me recall that in Z2, any subgroup is isomorphic to Z2, or a cyclic subgroup, or a product of two cyclic subgroups.
But here, H is generated by three elements, but since H must be a subgroup of Z2, which is free abelian of rank 2, H itself must be a free abelian group of rank at most 2.
Therefore, H is isomorphic to Z2 if the generators are linearly independent over Z, or else it is isomorphic to Z if they are dependent, but H is a subgroup of Z2, so more likely, H can be expressed as the set of all integer linear combinations of two vectors, which form a basis for H.
Similarly, H_{xy} is generated by (0, x) and (1, y).
Let's denote these generators as e1 = (0, x) and e2 = (1, y).
Then, H_{xy} is the set of all integer combinations a*e1 + b*e2 = (b, a*x + b*y).
So, any element in H_{xy} has the first component equal to any integer b, and the second component equal to a*x + b*y, where a and b are integers.
Now, since H has to equal H_{xy}, this tells us that the generators of H, namely (3,8), (4,-1), and (5,4), must be expressible as integer combinations of e1 and e2, and conversely, e1 and e2 must be expressible as integer combinations of the generators of H.
Therefore, to find H_{xy} such that H=H_{xy}, we need to determine x and y such that:
1. The generators of H are in H_{xy}, and
2. The generators of H_{xy} are in H.
But since H is generated by (3,8), (4,-1), and (5,4), which implies H is actually generated by all integer linear combinations of these three elements.
However, since these are elements of Z2, the subgroup they generate can be also generated by two elements (by the structure theorem for finitely generated abelian groups), or even a single element if they are all multiples of some element.
But in this case, since we have three generators in Z2, likely H is generated by two of them, or by some combination.
But maybe an easier approach is to recall that in Z2, any subgroup is of the form aZ × bZ or some diagonal subgroup, but more precisely, every subgroup H of Z2 can be expressed as all pairs (k, l) such that some linear combination of k and l is a multiple of a fixed integer.
Wait, actually, by the structure theorem, any subgroup of Z2 is free abelian of rank ≤ 2, so it's either trivial, cyclic, or isomorphic to Z2.
However, since our H is generated by three elements in Z2, which is itself a free abelian group of rank 2, so H must have rank at most 2.
But, given that we have three elements, perhaps the three generators can be reduced to two generators.
Alternatively, perhaps H can be expressed as the set of all (m, n) in Z2 such that pm + qn = 0 for some integers p and q, but I'm not sure.
Wait, let me step back.
To find H_{xy} such that H = H_{xy}, we need that H_{xy} is generated by (0, x) and (1, y).
Let's characterize H_{xy} first.
If H_{xy} is generated by (0, x) and (1, y), then elements of H_{xy} are of the form (b, a x + b y) for integers a, b.
So the first component can be any integer b, and the second component is a x + b y.
But since a can be any integer, a x can take any multiple of x.
So, the second component can be expressed as multiple of x plus multiple of y.
Wait, actually, if a and b are integers, then a x + b y = s x + t y where s = a and t = b.
So in fact, the second component can be any integer combination of x and y.
However, since in the first component we have b, and in the second component we have s x + t y where s is related to a.
Wait, actually, if we consider the elements as (b, a x + b y), since when we take a*(0, x) + b*(1, y), that's (b, a x + b y).
So the second component is a linear combination of x and y with coefficients a and b.
Therefore, the second component can reach any integer in the subgroup generated by x and y in Z.
If we think of the second component, it's xZ + yZ = gcd(x, y)Z.
So the second component is multiples of d = gcd(x, y).
However, the first component can be any integer b, since b is arbitrary.
Wait, but as per the element (b, a x + b y), if the first component is b, but if we can set a to any integer, given that b is chosen, can the second component be arbitrary?
Wait, for example, if we fix b, then the second component can be a x + b y.
So, for each fixed b, the second component can reach any multiple of x added to b y.
But if x and y are such that x and y are coprime, then for each b, a x + b y can take any integer congruent to b y mod x.
Therefore, if x divides b y, perhaps?
Hmm, maybe I need to think more clearly.
Wait, since the first component of H_{xy} is just any integer, because you can choose b to be any integer.
So for any integer k, you can have elements (k, n) where n is in xZ + y k.
Wait, if I take (k, n) = a*(0, x) + k*(1, y) = (k, a x + k y).
Therefore, yes, the first component is k, and the second component can be a x + k y for any integer a.
So, for each k, the second component can take any value in the coset k y + xZ.
So H_{xy} is the set of all (k, m) where m ≡ k y mod x.
Hence, H_{xy} is the set of pairs where the second component is congruent to k y mod x, where k is the first component.
Therefore, H_{xy} is equal to the set {(k, m) ∈ Z2 | m ≡ k y mod x}.
Therefore, if H is equal to H_{xy}, then H must be precisely this set.
That is, H is the set of all pairs (k, m) such that m ≡ k y mod x.
Therefore, equivalently, H is the kernel of the homomorphism φ: Z2 → Z/xZ defined by φ(k, m) = m - k y mod x.
Therefore, H = ker φ.
Alternatively, H is a subgroup of Z2 of index x if x ≠ 0, which in our case, since x > 0, we need x to be a positive integer such that H has index x in Z2.
Therefore, given our original generators (3,8), (4,-1), (5,4) must satisfy that 8 ≡ 3 y mod x, -1 ≡ 4 y mod x, and 4 ≡ 5 y mod x.
Because each of these elements must lie in H_{xy}, which is the set of pairs (k, m) with m ≡ y k mod x.
Therefore, for each generator (k, m), it must satisfy m ≡ y k mod x.
So, we have:
8 ≡ 3 y mod x,
-1 ≡ 4 y mod x,
4 ≡ 5 y mod x.
This gives us a system of congruences that we can solve for y modulo x, and x must be a positive integer such that these congruences hold.
So, x must be a common divisor of (8 - 3 y), ( -1 -4 y), (4 -5 y).
But since x divides all three differences, we can set up equations:
8 - 3 y ≡ 0 mod x,
-1 -4 y ≡ 0 mod x,
4 -5 y ≡ 0 mod x.
Therefore, these equations must all be satisfied.
Let's write these congruences as:
1) 3 y ≡ 8 mod x
2) 4 y ≡ -1 mod x
3) 5 y ≡ 4 mod x
So, we need to find integers x and y such that all three congruences hold.
Our goal is to find x and y with x > 0.
Therefore, each congruence can be rephrased as:
From 1): 3 y - 8 is divisible by x.
From 2): 4 y +1 is divisible by x.
From 3): 5 y -4 is divisible by x.
Therefore, x divides each of 3 y -8, 4 y +1, and 5 y -4.
So, let's denote:
3 y -8 = x * a
4 y +1 = x * b
5 y -4 = x * c
for some integers a, b, c.
Our goal is to solve for x, y.
Since x divides all three expressions, we can combine these equations.
First, let's eliminate y.
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Determine the divisibility constraint on x by eliminating y from 3y ≡ 8 mod x and 4y ≡ -1 mod x.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Determine the divisibility constraint on x by eliminating y from 3y ≡ 8 mod x and 5y ≡ 4 mod x.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: Expressions for y are derived from the congruences 3y ≡ 8 mod x and 4y ≡ -1 mod x, yielding y = (xa + 8)/3 and y = (xb - 1)/4 respectively. Equating these expressions gives (xa + 8)/3 = (xb - 1)/4. Cross-multiplication leads to 4(xa + 8) = 3(xb - 1). Expanding this results in the equation 4xa + 32 = 3xb - 3.
Rearranging the terms gives 4xa - 3xb + 35 = 0.
Factoring out x yields x(4a - 3b) = -35.
Therefore, x must be a divisor of -35.
Given that x is positive, x must be a positive divisor of 35.
The positive divisors of 35 are 1, 5, 7, and 35.
</Path>
<Path>
2: An expression for y is derived from 5y ≡ 4 mod x, giving y = (xc + 4)/5. Equating this with the expression from the first congruence, y = (xa + 8)/3, yields (xa + 8)/3 = (xc + 4)/5. Cross-multiplication results in 5(xa + 8) = 3(xc + 4). Expanding this gives 5xa + 40 = 3xc + 12. Rearranging terms leads to 5xa - 3xc + 28 = 0.
Factoring yields x(5a - 3c) = -28.
Consequently, x must be a divisor of -28.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The first path established that x must be a positive divisor of 35 (1, 5, 7, 35), while the second path showed that x must divide -28. Therefore, x must be a positive common divisor of 35 and 28.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
The positive divisors common to both 35 and 28 are 1 and 7.
So, x is either 1 or 7.
But x must be positive and also we need to find valid y.
Let's check x=7 first, as 1 is trivial?
Well, let's check both possibilities.
First, x=1:
If x=1, then from equation 1:
3y ≡8 mod1, but mod1 every integer is congruent, so this is trivially true.
Similarly, equation 2: 4y ≡-1 mod1 also holds, as does equation3.
Therefore, x=1 is technically possible.
However, H_xy would then be generated by (0,1) and (1,y).
But (0,1) and (1,y) in H_{xy} when x=1 implies that H_{1y} is the set {(b, a*1 + b*y) | a, b ∈ Z} = {(b, a + b y)}.
But since a is arbitrary, a + b y can be any integer, as we can adjust a to reach any integer.
Thus, H_{1y} is actually the entire Z2, because for any (k, m), you can choose b=k and a = m - k y, giving (k, m).
Therefore, H_{1y} = Z2.
However, is H equal to Z2?
Let's check.
If H is all integer combinations of (3,8), (4,-1), and (5,4).
To check if H is Z2, we can compute the determinant of the matrix formed by two of these vectors.
For instance, take (3,8) and (4,-1).
The determinant is 3*(-1) -4*8 = -3 -32 = -35.
The absolute value of the determinant is 35, which is the index of H in Z2 if they form a basis.
But since the determinant is -35, this means that H has index 35 in Z2.
So H is not the entire Z2, but a subgroup of index 35, hence H cannot be equal to H_{1y} which is all of Z2.
Hence, x=1 is invalid.
Therefore, x must be 7.
Let's check if x=7 is possible.
If x=7, then the three congruences must hold:
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Determine the value of y satisfying the congruence 3y ≡ 8 mod 7.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Determine the value of y satisfying the congruence 4y ≡ -1 mod 7.
</Outline>
<Outline>
3: Determine the value of y satisfying the congruence 5y ≡ 4 mod 7.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: The first congruence is 3y ≡ 8 mod 7. Since 8 ≡ 1 mod 7, this simplifies to 3y ≡ 1 mod 7. Multiplying by the inverse of 3 modulo 7, which is 5 (as 3 * 5 = 15 ≡ 1 mod 7), gives the solution. The result is y ≡ 5 * 1 mod 7. Thus, y ≡ 5 mod 7.
</Path>
<Path>
2: The second congruence is 4y ≡ -1 mod 7. Modulo 7, -1 is equivalent to 6. The congruence becomes 4y ≡ 6 mod 7. Multiplying by the inverse of 4 modulo 7, which is 2 (since 4 * 2 = 8 ≡ 1 mod 7), yields the solution. The calculation shows y ≡ 6 * 2 = 12 ≡ 5 mod 7. This confirms y ≡ 5 mod 7.
</Path>
<Path>
3: The third congruence is 5y ≡ 4 mod 7. Multiplying by the inverse of 5 modulo 7, which is 3 (since 5 * 3 = 15 ≡ 1 mod 7), leads to the solution. This gives y ≡ 4 * 3 = 12 ≡ 5 mod 7.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
All three congruences consistently yield the solution y ≡ 5 mod 7.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Hence, y≡5 mod7.
So when x=7, we need y=5 +7k for some integer k.
However, since we are to pick y such that H=H_{xy}.
Let's recall that H_{xy} is generated by (0,x)=(0,7) and (1,y).
If we take y=5, which is the minimal positive residue mod7, is that sufficient?
But perhaps we can choose y=5.
Let's check if generators (3,8), (4,-1), and (5,4) are in H_{7 5}. This ensures H ⊆ H_{7,5}.
Let me verify:
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Determine if (3,8) is an element of the subgroup H_{7,5}.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Determine if (4,-1) is an element of the subgroup H_{7,5}.
</Outline>
<Outline>
3: Determine if (5,4) is an element of the subgroup H_{7,5}.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: The element (3,8) is checked for membership in H_{7 5}. Elements of H_{7 5} have the form (b, a*7 + b*5) for integers a and b. We seek integers a and b such that b = 3 and 8 = 7a + 5b. Substituting b=3 into the second equation yields 8 = 7a + 15, which simplifies to 7a = -7, giving a = -1. With a=-1 and b=3, the element (3,8) is generated, confirming its presence in H_{7 5}.
</Path>
<Path>
2: The element (4,-1) is verified for inclusion in H_{7 5}. We require integers a and b such that b=4 and -1 = 7a + 5b. Substituting b=4 gives -1 = 7a + 20, leading to 7a = -21. This results in a = -3. With a=-3 and b=4, the element (4,-1) is constructed, indicating it belongs to H_{7 5}.
</Path>
<Path>
3: The element (5,4) is examined for membership in H_{7 5}. Integers a and b are sought such that b=5 and 4 = 7a + 5b. Substituting b=5 yields 4 = 7a + 25, which gives 7a = -21. This implies a = -3. Using a=-3 and b=5 generates (5,4), confirming its presence in H_{7 5}.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The generators (3,8), (4,-1), and (5,4) are all members of H_{7,5}. Consequently, the subgroup H generated by these elements is contained within H_{7,5}.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Now we need to check if the generators of H_{7 5}, which are (0,7) and (1,5), are in H. This ensures H_{7,5} ⊆ H.
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Determine if (0,7) is an integer linear combination of (3,8), (4,-1), and (5,4).
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Determine if (1,5) is an integer linear combination of (3,8), (4,-1), and (5,4).
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: The task is to determine if (0,7) can be expressed as an integer linear combination of (3,8), (4,-1), and (5,4). This requires finding integers a, b, c such that a*(3,8) + b*(4,-1) + c*(5,4) = (0,7). The corresponding system of linear equations is 3a + 4b + 5c = 0 and 8a - b + 4c = 7. The system involves two equations with three variables. Solving the first equation for 'a' yields 3a = -4b - 5c, or a = (-4b - 5c)/3.
Substituting 'a' into the second equation gives 8*(-4b - 5c)/3 - b + 4c = 7.
Multiplying by 3 eliminates the denominator: 8*(-4b - 5c) - 3b + 12c = 21.
Expanding and combining terms results in -32b - 40c - 3b + 12c = 21, which simplifies to -35b - 28c = 21.
Dividing by -7 yields the Diophantine equation 5b + 4c = -3.
Integer solutions for b and c are required for this equation.
Solving for b gives 5b = -3 - 4c, so b = (-3 - 4c)/5.
For b to be an integer, -3 - 4c must be divisible by 5.
This leads to the congruence -3 - 4c ≡ 0 mod 5, which simplifies to 4c ≡ 2 mod 5.
Multiplying by 4 (the inverse of 4 mod 5) gives c ≡ 8 ≡ 3 mod 5.
Therefore, c can be written as c = 3 + 5k for some integer k.
Substituting c back into the expression for b gives b = (-3 - 4*(3+5k))/5 = (-15 - 20k)/5 = -3 - 4k.
Substituting b and c back into the expression for a yields a = (-4*(-3 - 4k) - 5*(3 + 5k))/3 = (12 + 16k - 15 - 25k)/3 = (-3 - 9k)/3 = -1 - 3k.
The general integer solution is (a, b, c) = (-1 - 3k, -3 - 4k, 3 + 5k).
Setting k=0 gives a particular solution (a, b, c) = (-1, -3, 3).
Verifying this solution: 3*(-1) + 4*(-3) + 5*(3) = -3 - 12 + 15 = 0.
The first component is correct.
Checking the second component: 8*(-1) - (-3) + 4*(3) = -8 + 3 + 12 = 7.
The second component is also correct.
The specific coefficients (a, b, c) = (-1, -3, 3) satisfy the system.
Thus, (0,7) = -1*(3,8) - 3*(4,-1) + 3*(5,4) = (-3, -8) + (-12, 3) + (15, 12) = (0, 7).
This confirms that (0,7) is indeed an integer linear combination of the generators.
Therefore, (0,7) is an element of H.
</Path>
<Path>
2: The goal is to verify if (1,5) can be expressed as an integer linear combination of (3,8), (4,-1), and (5,4). This requires finding integers a, b, c satisfying 3a + 4b + 5c = 1 and 8a - b + 4c = 5. This is another system of two linear equations with three variables. Solving the first equation for 'a' yields 3a = 1 - 4b - 5c, so a = (1 - 4b - 5c)/3. Substituting this expression for 'a' into the second equation gives 8*(1 - 4b - 5c)/3 - b + 4c = 5.
Multiplying the equation by 3 results in 8*(1 - 4b - 5c) - 3b + 12c = 15.
Expanding the equation gives 8 - 32b - 40c - 3b + 12c = 15.
Combining like terms simplifies the equation to -35b - 28c = 7.
Dividing the equation by -7 yields 5b + 4c = -1.
Solving this Diophantine equation for b gives 5b = -1 - 4c, leading to b = (-1 - 4c)/5.
For b to be an integer, -1 - 4c must be divisible by 5, which means -1 - 4c ≡ 0 mod 5.
This simplifies to the congruence 4c ≡ -1 ≡ 4 mod 5.
Multiplying by the inverse of 4 mod 5 (which is 4) gives c ≡ 16 ≡ 1 mod 5.
Therefore, c can be expressed as c = 1 + 5k for some integer k.
Substituting c back into the expression for b yields b = (-1 - 4*(1 + 5k))/5 = (-5 - 20k)/5 = -1 - 4k.
Substituting b and c back into the expression for a results in a = (1 - 4*(-1 - 4k) - 5*(1 + 5k))/3 = (1 + 4 + 16k - 5 - 25k)/3 = (-9k)/3 = -3k.
The general integer solution is (a, b, c) = (-3k, -1 - 4k, 1 + 5k).
Choosing k=0 provides a particular solution (a, b, c) = (0, -1, 1).
Verifying this solution: 0*(3,8) - 1*(4,-1) + 1*(5,4) = (0,0) + (-4,1) + (5,4) = (1, 5).
The calculation confirms the combination is correct.
Therefore, (1,5) is expressible as 0*(3,8) - 1*(4,-1) + 1*(5,4).
This demonstrates that (1,5) is an element of H.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The element (0,7) is in H as it equals -1*(3,8) - 3*(4,-1) + 3*(5,4). The element (1,5) is in H as it equals 0*(3,8) - 1*(4,-1) + 1*(5,4). Both generators of H_{7,5} belong to H, implying H_{7,5} is a subset of H.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Therefore, the generators of H_{7 5} are in H.
Since H is generated by the three elements (3,8), (4,-1), and (5,4), and H_{7 5} is generated by (0,7) and (1,5), and we've shown mutual containment: every generator of H is in H_{7 5} and vice versa, so H=H_{7 5}.
Therefore, the pair (x,y)=(7,5) satisfies H=H_{xy}.
So to confirm, in this case, x=7, y=5, with x>0.
Therefore, the answer is (7, 5).
</Think>