<Think>
Okay, let me try to work through this problem step by step. So we're looking for a three-term strictly increasing arithmetic sequence of integers. Let's break down what that means first. An arithmetic sequence has a common difference between consecutive terms. Since it's strictly increasing, the common difference must be a positive integer.
Let's denote the three terms. If the middle term is, say, \( a \), then the first term would be \( a - d \) and the third term would be \( a + d \), where \( d \) is the common difference. But wait, actually in an arithmetic sequence, the common difference is the difference between consecutive terms, right? So the first term would be the middle term minus the common difference, and the third term would be the middle term plus the common difference. That makes sense. So the three terms are \( a - d \), \( a \), \( a + d \), all integers, and \( d \) is a positive integer since the sequence is strictly increasing.
The problem states that the sum of the squares of the three terms equals the product of the middle term and the square of the common difference. Let me write that equation out. The sum of the squares is \( (a - d)^2 + a^2 + (a + d)^2 \), and this should equal \( a \times d^2 \). So putting it all together, we have: \[ (a - d)^2 + a^2 + (a + d)^2 = a d^2 \]
Now my goal is to find all such sequences, which means finding all pairs \( (a, d) \) where \( a \) and \( d \) are integers with \( d > 0 \), and then find the sum of all third terms, which would be \( a + d \). So once I find all possible \( (a, d) \), I need to compute \( a + d \) for each and add them up. First, let's expand the left-hand side (LHS) of the equation:
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Determine the algebraic expansion of the term \( (a - d)^2 \).
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Determine the algebraic expansion of the term \( (a + d)^2 \).
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: The algebraic expansion of \( (a - d)^2 \) is \( a^2 - 2ad + d^2 \).
</Path>
<Path>
2: The algebraic expansion of \( (a + d)^2 \) is \( a^2 + 2ad + d^2 \).
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The term \( (a - d)^2 \) expands to \( a^2 - 2ad + d^2 \), and the term \( (a + d)^2 \) expands to \( a^2 + 2ad + d^2 \).
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
\[ (a - d)^2 + a^2 + (a + d)^2 = (a^2 - 2ad + d^2) + a^2 + (a^2 + 2ad + d^2) \] Let me compute each term: 1. \( (a - d)^2 = a^2 - 2ad + d^2 \) 2. \( a^2 = a^2 \) 3. \( (a + d)^2 = a^2 + 2ad + d^2 \)
Adding them together: \( a^2 - 2ad + d^2 + a^2 + a^2 + 2ad + d^2 \) Let's combine like terms: - \( a^2 + a^2 + a^2 = 3a^2 \) - \( -2ad + 2ad = 0 \) (they cancel out) - \( d^2 + d^2 = 2d^2 \) So the left-hand side simplifies to \( 3a^2 + 2d^2 \).
Thus, the equation becomes: \[ 3a^2 + 2d^2 = a d^2 \]
Let me rearrange this equation to collect like terms.
Subtract \( a d^2 \) from both sides: \[ 3a^2 + 2d^2 - a d^2 = 0 \\ 3a^2 + (2 - a) d^2 = 0 \] Hmmm, not sure if that's immediately helpful.
Maybe I should bring all terms to one side: \[ 3a^2 + 2d^2 = a d^2 \\ 3a^2 = a d^2 - 2d^2 \\ 3a^2 = d^2(a - 2) \] So now, 3a2 equals d2 times (a - 2).
Let me note this as: \[ 3a^2 = d^2(a - 2) \] This seems more manageable. Let's rearrange to get variables on one side if possible. Perhaps, solve for d2. So: \[ d^2 = \frac{3a^2}{a - 2} \]
But since \( d^2 \) must be a positive integer (as d is an integer, common difference positive), the right side must also be a positive integer. Therefore, \( \frac{3a^2}{a - 2} \) must be a positive integer. Moreover, the term \( a - 2 \) must divide \( 3a^2 \). So, \( a - 2 \) divides \( 3a^2 \), which puts constraints on the possible values of \( a \). Given that \( d \) must be a positive integer, the expression \( \frac{3a^2}{a - 2} \) must also be a perfect square. Therefore, \( \frac{3a^2}{a - 2} \) is a perfect square. So, we now need to find all integer values of \( a (a > 2 \), since the denominator \( a - 2 \) must be positive otherwise \( d^2 \) would be negative or zero, which can't happen), such that \( \frac{3 a^2}{a - 2} \) is a perfect square. That's a bit complicated, but maybe we can manipulate the equation to get it into a more manageable form. Let's write it again: \[ 3 a^2 = d^2 (a - 2) \] Therefore, \( a - 2 \) must divide 3 a2. Since \( a \) is an integer greater than 2 (since \( a - 2 \) must be positive, as the denominator must not be zero or negative because \( d^2 must be positive), we can think perhaps that \( a - 2 \) and \( a \) are coprime? But not necessarily. Let's note that \( \gcd(a - 2, a) \). Since \( \gcd(a - 2, a) = \gcd(a - 2, 2) \). So if \( a - 2 \) is even, then \( \gcd(a -2, a) = 2 \); if \( a -2 \) is odd, then \( \gcd(a -2, a) = 1 \). This is via Euclidean algorithm. Thus, depending on whether \( a - 2 \) is even or odd, the GCD can be either 1 or 2. Let me explore this. So suppose that \( a - 2 \) and \( a \) have gcd of 1 or 2. Rewriting \( a \) in terms of \( a -2 \): but perhaps it's better to consider variables here. Let’s denote \( k = a - 2 \), so that \( a = k + 2 \).
Then substituting into the equation: \[ 3(k + 2)^2 = d^2 k \]
Therefore, \( d^2 = \frac{3(k + 2)^2}{k} \)
Which we can write as: \[ d^2 = 3 \left( \frac{(k + 2)^2}{k} \right ) = 3 \left( \frac{k^2 + 4k + 4}{k} \right ) = 3 \left( k + 4 + \frac{4}{k} \right ) \]
Since \( d^2 \) must be an integer, \( 3 \left( k +4 + \frac{4}{k} \right ) \), this fraction \(\frac{4}{k} \) must be an integer.
Therefore, \( k \) must divide 4.
But \( k = a - 2 \) must be a positive integer (since \( a > 2 \)), and 4 is positive.
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: The possible positive integer values for k, given that k must divide 4.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: The implications of the determined k values potentially not yielding solutions and the validity of the current approach.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: The integer k must divide 4, meaning the possible positive divisors of 4 are 1, 2, and 4. Consequently, k can be 1, 2, or 4.
</Path>
<Path>
2: This approach initially suggests that there might be no valid sequences. However, this outcome is questionable because an arithmetic sequence satisfying the conditions could exist, implying a potential error in the current reasoning.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The condition that k divides 4 and k is positive yields possible k values of {1, 2, 4}. However, there's a concern that these k values may not lead to valid solutions, indicating a possible flaw in the current reasoning or a missed step.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Let me check my substitution. Hold on, let's go back. Wait, perhaps after substituting \( k = a -2 \), perhaps I should have done a different step. Let's step back. Original equation when substituting \( a = k + 2 \): \[ d^2 = \frac{3(k + 2)^2}{k} \] Therefore: \[ d^2 = 3 \times \frac{(k + 2)^2}{k} \] In order for this to be a perfect square, the fraction \( (k + 2)^2 / k \) multiplied by 3 must result in a perfect square. Note that \( (k + 2)^2 / k \) can be written as \( (k^2 +4k +4)/k = k + 4 + 4/k \). Therefore, \( 4/k \) must be an integer. So \( k | 4 \). So possible k s: 1,2,4. So similar as above. But in each case, 3*(k +4 +4/k) gives 27, 24,27, none perfect squares. Wait, maybe my substitution forced k to be positive integers, but there might be other possibilities if k divides 4 but maybe negative. Wait, but because k = a - 2, and a >2, so k must be positive. So k can't be negative. Hence k must be positive divisors of 4. So from this approach, the possible k=1,2,4 lead to a =3,4,6 and d^2=27,24,27, but these not being perfect squares implies there are no solutions, which contradicts the problem statement which says "Find the sum of the third terms of all special sequences." Wait, the problem must have solutions. Therefore, perhaps I've made an incorrect assumption somewhere. Let me check. Original substitution: s/pose we denote middle term as a, common difference as d. Three terms are a -d, a, a +d. But since the sequence is strictly increasing, d must be a positive integer. (Problem statement says it's of integers.) Sum of the squares equals product of middle term and square of common difference. So: (a−d)^2 + a^2 + (a+d)^2 = a d^2. I then expanded that to get: 3a2 + 2d2 = a d2. 3a2 -a d2 + 2d2 =0. 3a2 = d2(a -2) Thus, d2 = 3a2/(a -2) Therefore, 3a2/(a -2) must be a perfect square. To be a perfect square, all the exponents in prime decomposition of the expression must be even. So, writing in terms of k: a -2 =k, so a= k +2. Then substituting back in. So 3(k +2)^2 /k must be a perfect square. Hence, I did correctly. Therefore in each possible divisor of k=1,2,4, the output isn't a perfect square. Therefore, thus no solutions? But since the problem asks us to find the sum of the third terms of all special sequences, meaning there must be at least one. So perhaps my substitution is wrong, or miscalculations in previous steps. Wait maybe in my step when I had: 3a2 = d2(a -2). Rewriting this as: 3a2 = d2(a -2) But possible variables could be reframed.
Test possible values for \( k \).
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Determine the value of d-squared when k=1.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Determine the value of d-squared when k=2.
</Outline>
<Outline>
3: Determine the value of d-squared when k=4.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: When k=1, it follows that a=3. Substituting k=1 and a=3 into the expression for d-squared, 3*(k + 4 + 4/k), yields 3*(1 + 4 + 4/1), which simplifies to 3*(1+4+4) = 3*9 = 27. Thus, d-squared is 27.
</Path>
<Path>
2: For k=2, the value of a is 4. The expression for d-squared, 3*(k + 4 + 4/k), becomes 3*(2 + 4 + 4/2), which evaluates to 3*(2 + 4 + 2) = 3*8 = 24.
</Path>
<Path>
3: If k=4, then a equals 6. Calculating d-squared using the formula 3*(k + 4 + 4/k) results in 3*(4 + 4 + 4/4), which simplifies to 3*(4 + 4 + 1) = 3*9 = 27.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The value of d-squared is 27 for k=1 (where a=3), 24 for k=2 (where a=4), and 27 for k=4 (where a=6).
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Check if \( d^2 \) results are perfect squares.
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Determine if d-squared = 27, corresponding to k=1, is a perfect square.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Determine if d-squared = 24, corresponding to k=2, is a perfect square.
</Outline>
<Outline>
3: Determine if d-squared = 27, corresponding to k=4, is a perfect square.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: The value 27 is not a perfect square, as its square root, √27, simplifies to 3√3, which is not an integer. This invalidates the case where k=1.
</Path>
<Path>
2: The value 24 is not a perfect square since its square root, √24, is approximately 4.899. Consequently, the case where k=2 is invalid.
</Path>
<Path>
3: The value 27 is not a perfect square, rendering the case for k=4 invalid.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The d-squared values of 27 (for k=1), 24 (for k=2), and 27 (for k=4) are not perfect squares, rendering each corresponding k value invalid.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Conclude (incorrectly) no solutions from this method.
Alternatively, let me rearrange and solve for a.
3a2 - (d2)a + 2d2 =0.
This is a quadratic in terms of a.
So quadratic equation in a: 3a2 - (d2)a + 2d2 =0. Let me try solving for a:
Using quadratic formula, a = [d2 ± sqrt(d^4 - 24d2)]/(6)
Hmmm.
That seems complicated, but sqrt part must be integer.
Simplify discriminant: sqrt(d^4 -24d2) = d sqrt(d2 -24)
Therefore, discriminant must be integer.
Therefore, d2 -24 must be a perfect square.
Let’s let k = d, then d2-24 must be a perfect square.
Let me denote m2 = d2 -24.
So d2 - m2 =24.
Which factors as (d - m)(d + m)=24.
Since d and m are positive integers, with d >m.
So find factors of 24 where (d -m) and (d + m) are factors.
We can list the factor pairs of 24:
1×24,
2×12,
3×8,
4×6.
Also, considering d - m and d + m are both positive and both even (since d and m are both integers, so d -m and d + m have the same parity.
Since their product is 24, which is even, both factors must be even. Thus, the possible factor pairs: 2×12 and 4×6. Let's check these.
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Determination of d, m, and a, and verification of the arithmetic sequence for the factor pair (2, 12).
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Determination of d, m, and a, and verification of the arithmetic sequence for the factor pair (4, 6).
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: The factor pair (2, 12) implies d - m = 2 and d + m = 12. Adding these equations yields 2d = 14, so d = 7. Substituting d = 7 into d - m = 2 gives m = 5. Verifying these values, m² = 25 and d² = 49. Consequently, d² - 24 equals 49 - 24, which is 25, confirming m² = 25.
This equality (25=25) validates the values of d and m.
For d=7, the quadratic equation for a is 3a² - 49a + 2(49) = 0, which simplifies to 3a² - 49a + 98 = 0.
The discriminant of this quadratic equation is 49² - 4(3)(98), which equals 2401 - 1176 = 1225.
The square root of the discriminant (1225) is 35.
The solutions for a are given by (49 ± 35) / 6.
This yields two possible values for a: (49 + 35) / 6 = 84 / 6 = 14, and (49 - 35) / 6 = 14 / 6.
The value 14/6 is not an integer.
Therefore, the only integer solution for a is 14.
This leads to the arithmetic sequence (a-d, a, a+d) as (14-7, 14, 14+7), which is [7, 14, 21].
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1.1: Calculation of the sum of squares for the sequence [7, 14, 21].
</Outline>
<Outline>
1.2: Calculation of the product of the middle term and the square of the common difference for the sequence [7, 14, 21].
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1.1: The sum of squares for the sequence [7, 14, 21] is calculated as 7² + 14² + 21², which equals 49 + 196 + 441, resulting in 686.
</Path>
<Path>
1.2: The product of the middle term (14) and the square of the common difference (7²) is 14 × 49, which equals 686.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
For the arithmetic sequence [7, 14, 21], the sum of the squares of its terms is 686, and the product of its middle term and the square of its common difference is also 686.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
The condition that the sum of squares equals the product of the middle term and the square of the common difference (686 = 686) is satisfied.
</Path>
<Path>
2: The factor pair (4, 6) implies d - m = 4 and d + m = 6. Adding these equations yields 2d = 10, so d = 5. Substituting d = 5 into d - m = 4 gives m = 1. Verifying these values, m² = 1. Also, d² - 24 equals 25 - 24, which is 1, confirming m² = 1.
This confirms the validity of d=5 and m=1.
With d=5, the quadratic equation for a, 3a² - d²a + 2d² = 0, becomes 3a² - 25a + 2(25) = 0, simplifying to 3a² - 25a + 50 = 0.
The discriminant of this quadratic is 25² - 4(3)(50), which equals 625 - 600 = 25.
The square root of the discriminant (25) is 5.
The solutions for a are given by (25 ± 5) / 6.
This results in two possible values for a: (25 + 5) / 6 = 30 / 6 = 5, and (25 - 5) / 6 = 20 / 6.
The value 20/6 is not an integer.
Therefore, the only integer solution for a is 5.
This leads to the arithmetic sequence (a-d, a, a+d) as (5-5, 5, 5+5), which is [0, 5, 10].
The terms [0, 5, 10] are integers, and the sequence is strictly increasing as the common difference d=5 is positive.
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
2.1: Calculation of the sum of squares for the sequence [0, 5, 10].
</Outline>
<Outline>
2.2: Calculation of the product of the middle term and the square of the common difference for the sequence [0, 5, 10].
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
2.1: The sum of squares for the sequence [0, 5, 10] is 0² + 5² + 10², which equals 0 + 25 + 100, resulting in 125.
</Path>
<Path>
2.2: The product of the middle term (5) and the square of the common difference (5²) is 5 × 25, which equals 125.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
For the arithmetic sequence [0, 5, 10], the sum of the squares of its terms is 125, and the product of its middle term and the square of its common difference is also 125.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
The condition that the sum of squares equals the product of the middle term and the square of the common difference (125 = 125) is satisfied.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The factor pair (2, 12) results in d=7 and m=5, yielding an integer middle term a=14 and the valid arithmetic sequence [7, 14, 21]. The factor pair (4, 6) results in d=5 and m=1, yielding an integer middle term a=5 and the valid arithmetic sequence [0, 5, 10].
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Thus we have two sequences: [0,5,10] and [7,14,21]. But wait, the first term in the first sequence is zero. Since the problem doesn't specify that the terms have to be positive integers, just integers. Thus 0 is allowed. So these are the two special sequences. Wait. So third terms are 10 and 21, sum is 31. But before concluding, should check if these are all possible solutions. Because we considered k= m where d^2 -24=m2. Factor pairs: original equation with factors 1×24, 3×8, but we dismissed them because (correctly) d and m are both integers, so d -m and d +m must both be even. Thus 1×24: since 24 can't be written as two factors of same parity if factors are 1 and24 (1 odd,24 even, different parity). Similarly, 3×8: 3 is odd,8 is even. Hence, they do not have the same parity, leading to different sums, so discarded. Therefore only factor pairs where the elements are even would work: 2×12,4×6. So that gives us two possibilities: d=7 and d=5. As we saw. But what if we considered reversing the order? No, because \( d\ge m +1 \). Hence, those are the only two possibilities. Thus, sequences with third terms 10 and 21. Hence the sum is 10+21=31. Wait, but in the first sequence [0,5,10], 0 is allowed but the common difference is 5. Wait, but the problem says three-term strictly increasing arithmetic sequence of integers. No restrictions on terms being positive. So yeah, both sequences are valid. Hence, sum is 10+21=31. So answer would be 31? But wait let's confirm once again. Wait the first sequence has first term 0 (allowed, as integers can be non-positive). The sequence is 0,5,10. Common difference 5. Arithmetic. Sum of squares: 02 +52 +102=125. Product of middle term (5) by square of difference (25): 5×25=125. OK, same as previous. Second sequence: 7,14,21. Common difference 7. Sum of squares:72=49,142=196,212=441. Sum:49+196=245,245+441=686. Product of middle term 14 by 49(square of difference)=14×49=686. Valid. Hence those two sequences. But wait, in our solving via the factoring approach, we found two solutions. Is there another scenario when the quadratic can have integer solutions? How did we get k= 7 and 5. That's through considering d via such factorization.
Alternatively, If I go back to the first approach where we set k =a -2, but all k solutions gave invalid d^2. However after this quadratic approach I found two valid solutions. So my two approaches led to different conclusions, but given that [0,5,10] and [7,14,21] exist, I must reconcile why substituting k =a -2 led to 3 solutions, but none led to d2 being square. But wait maybe I conflated variables here. Wait in the first approach, k=a-2, but in quadratic approach, we called k=d. So variables got flipped. Probably that was the confusion. Hence that first approach of substituting k= a-2 led to d squared being non-integers. But where in the quadratic approach we found valid sequences. So the error in the first approach is maybe because setting k= a -2 and considering the expression 3* that but neglecting that maybe the divisors of 4 don't account for other possibilities. Indeed,a s found here (a=5 and a=14). Let's verify if \( a=5 \): then k=5 -2=3. Which would imply k=3, thus would not divide 4. So contradicts the first reasoning. Thus, first approach was flawed. Thus, my first approach where k divides 4 is not exhaustive because although d2 must be integer, the ratio might have denominator canceled through factors of 3 for the expression to be a square. Because while in the first approach I assumed that from 3a2/(a -2), k divides 4 but that's incorrect. Actually, 3 maybe can supply factors such that even if a-2 divides 3a2, k =a -2 doesn’t have to divide 4 necessarily. Instead, perhaps by considering their greatest common divisor.
Since d^2=3a2/(a -2), in here, 3a squared over (a -2).
Factor. gcd(a-2, a) = gcd(a-2,2). Which is 1 or 2. Thus. So, if k=a -2, then gcd(k, a) =gcd(k,k +2)= gcd(k,2). Thus, either 1 or 2 depending on k. Then, since k divides 3a2, but since k divides 3a2 and since gcd(k,2) is 1 or 2, let's split into cases.
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Determination of valid integer values for a and d when k (where k = a-2) is even.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Determination of valid integer values for a and d when k (where k = a-2) is odd.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: If k is even, it can be expressed as k=2m for some positive integer m; the formula for d-squared becomes d^2 = 3(k+2)^2/k = 3(2m+2)^2/(2m) = 6(m+1)^2/m. For d-squared to be an integer, m must divide 6(m+1)^2. Since m and m+1 are coprime, m must divide 6. The positive integer divisors of 6 are m=1, 2, 3, and 6.
These m values correspond to k=2m values of 2, 4, 6, and 12 respectively, and consequently a=k+2 values of 4, 6, 8, and 14.
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1.1: Determination of whether d-squared is a perfect square for m=1 (k=2, a=4).
</Outline>
<Outline>
1.2: Determination of whether d-squared is a perfect square for m=2 (k=4, a=6).
</Outline>
<Outline>
1.3: Determination of whether d-squared is a perfect square for m=3 (k=6, a=8).
</Outline>
<Outline>
1.4: Determination of whether d-squared is a perfect square for m=6 (k=12, a=14).
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1.1: For m=1, which corresponds to k=2 and a=4, d-squared is calculated as 6*(1+1)^2/1, resulting in 24. This value is not a perfect square, so this case is not valid.
</Path>
<Path>
1.2: For m=2, corresponding to k=4 and a=6, d-squared is 6*(2+1)^2/2, which equals 27. This is not a perfect square, rendering this case invalid.
</Path>
<Path>
1.3: If m=3, then k=6 and a=8, leading to d-squared being 6*(3+1)^2/3, or 32. Since 32 is not a perfect square, this case is invalid.
</Path>
<Path>
1.4: When m=6, k is 12 and a is 14; d-squared is 6*(6+1)^2/6, which simplifies to 49. As 49 is the square of 7, d is 7, a positive integer.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
For m=1, 2, and 3 (corresponding to (k=2, a=4), (k=4, a=6), and (k=6, a=8) respectively), the calculated d-squared values (24, 27, 32) are not perfect squares. For m=6 (k=12, a=14), d-squared is 49, which is a perfect square, yielding d=7.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
The case a=14 with d=7 is valid, leading to the arithmetic sequence (14-7, 14, 14+7), which is [7, 14, 21]. This matches a previously identified solution and corresponds to d=7 and a=14 from an alternative solution method.
</Path>
<Path>
2: If k is odd, its greatest common divisor with 2 is 1, and the equation for d-squared is d^2 = 3(k+2)^2/k. Since k is odd, gcd(k, k+2) = gcd(k, 2) = 1. Because k divides 3(k+2)^2 and k is coprime with (k+2)^2, k must divide 3. The positive odd integer divisors of 3 are k=1 and k=3.
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
2.1: Determination of whether d-squared is a perfect square for k=1 (a=3).
</Outline>
<Outline>
2.2: Determination of whether d-squared is a perfect square for k=3 (a=5).
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
2.1: For k=1, where a=3, d-squared is calculated as 3*(1+2)^2/1, which equals 27. This value is not a perfect square.
</Path>
<Path>
2.2: If k=3, then a=5; d-squared is 3*(3+2)^2/3, resulting in 25. Since 25 is a perfect square, d is 5.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
For k=1 (a=3), d-squared is 27, which is not a perfect square. For k=3 (a=5), d-squared is 25, which is a perfect square, yielding d=5.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
The case k=3 results in a=5 and d=5, which gives the arithmetic sequence (5-5, 5, 5+5), or [0, 5, 10]. This is another previously identified solution.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
When k (representing a-2) is even, further analysis showed that m (where k=2m) must divide 6; among the possible values, only m=6 (k=12, a=14) yields a perfect square for d-squared (d^2=49, d=7), leading to the sequence [7, 14, 21]. When k is odd, k must divide 3; only k=3 (a=5) results in a perfect square for d-squared (d^2=25, d=5), producing the sequence [0, 5, 10].
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Therefore considering both cases for even and odd k=a -2, we find that for even k=12 (gives sequences [7,14,21]) and odd k=3 (gives [0,5,10]). Thus, this approach via case matching gives the two solutions that the quadratic approach found.
So combining cases, total solutions are two, leading to third terms of 10 and21.
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: The sum of the third terms from the identified valid sequences.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: The final answer derived from the sum of the third terms.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: The summation of the identified third terms, 10 and 21, results in 31.
</Path>
<Path>
2: The final answer, based on this calculation, is 31.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
The sum of the third terms from the valid sequences is 31, which constitutes the final answer.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
But wait the system wants the answer in boxed. So likely \boxed{31}.
But another cross-check: check initial values. Another thought: When I considered factor pairs (thinking when equating equations, sometimes solutions can pop up when terms are re-oriented. For instance, trying small common differences. Let me brute-force check small d's to see. Let’s guess d starting from1:
Let's think in parallel.
<Parallel>
<Goal>
<Outline>
1: Determination of integer solutions for 'a' under the condition that the common difference d=1.
</Outline>
<Outline>
2: Determination of integer solutions for 'a' under the condition that the common difference d=2.
</Outline>
<Outline>
3: Determination of integer solutions for 'a' under the condition that the common difference d=3.
</Outline>
<Outline>
4: Determination of integer solutions for 'a' under the condition that the common difference d=4.
</Outline>
<Outline>
5: Determination of integer solutions for 'a' and the resulting arithmetic sequence under the condition that the common difference d=5.
</Outline>
<Outline>
6: Determination of integer solutions for 'a' under the condition that the common difference d=6.
</Outline>
<Outline>
7: Determination of integer solutions for 'a' and the resulting arithmetic sequence under the condition that the common difference d=7.
</Outline>
<Outline>
8: Determination of integer solutions for 'a' under the condition that the common difference d=8.
</Outline>
</Goal>
<Path>
1: For a common difference d=1, the governing equation 3a² = d²(a-2) translates to 3a² = 1²(a-2), or 3a² = a-2. This rearranges into the quadratic equation 3a² - a + 2 = 0. The discriminant for this quadratic is (-1)² - 4(3)(2) = 1 - 24 = -23. As the discriminant is negative, there are no real solutions for 'a', and consequently, no integer solutions exist for this case.
</Path>
<Path>
2: With a common difference d=2, the equation 3a² = d²(a-2) becomes 3a² = 2²(a-2), which is 3a² = 4(a-2) or 3a² = 4a - 8. This can be written as the quadratic equation 3a² - 4a + 8 = 0. The discriminant is (-4)² - 4(3)(8) = 16 - 96 = -80, which is negative, indicating no real solutions for 'a'.
</Path>
<Path>
3: When the common difference d=3, the equation 3a² = d²(a-2) becomes 3a² = 3²(a-2), or 3a² = 9(a-2). This simplifies to 3a² = 9a - 18, which can be rearranged to 3a² - 9a + 18 = 0. The discriminant is (-9)² - 4(3)(18) = 81 - 216 = -135, so there are no real solutions for 'a'.
</Path>
<Path>
4: For a common difference d=4, the equation 3a² = d²(a-2) is 3a² = 4²(a-2), or 3a² = 16(a-2). This gives 3a² = 16a - 32, which rearranges to the quadratic equation 3a² - 16a + 32 = 0. The discriminant is (-16)² - 4(3)(32) = 256 - 384 = -128, indicating no real solutions for 'a'.
</Path>
<Path>
5: If the common difference d=5, the equation 3a² = d²(a-2) becomes 3a² = 5²(a-2), or 3a² = 25(a-2), simplifying to 3a² - 25a + 50 = 0. The solutions for 'a' are (25 ± √((-25)² - 4(3)(50))) / (2*3), which results in (25 ± 5) / 6. This yields integer solution a=5 (from (25+5)/6) and non-integer 20/6, thus a=5 is the only integer solution. This leads to the arithmetic sequence (5-5, 5, 5+5), or [0, 5, 10], which satisfies the problem's conditions.
</Path>
<Path>
6: For a common difference d=6, the equation 3a² = d²(a-2) translates to 3a² = 6²(a-2), or 3a² = 36(a-2), becoming 3a² - 36a + 72 = 0. This simplifies to a² - 12a + 24 = 0 upon division by 3. The discriminant for this quadratic is (-12)² - 4(1)(24) = 144 - 96 = 48, and its square root, √48 = 4√3, is not an integer. Consequently, 'a' is not an integer in this case.
</Path>
<Path>
7: When the common difference d=7, the equation 3a² = d²(a-2) becomes 3a² = 7²(a-2), leading to 3a² = 49(a-2), or 3a² - 49a + 98 = 0. Solving this quadratic equation for 'a' yields (49 ± √((-49)² - 4(3)(98))) / (2*3), which simplifies to (49 ± 35) / 6. One integer solution is a = (49+35)/6 = 14, while the other solution, (49-35)/6 = 14/6, is not an integer. This value a=14 corresponds to a valid arithmetic sequence.
</Path>
<Path>
8: With a common difference d=8, the equation 3a² = d²(a-2) becomes 3a² = 8²(a-2), or 3a² = 64(a-2), rearranging to 3a² - 64a + 128 = 0. The discriminant is (-64)² - 4(3)(128) = 4096 - 1536 = 2560. Since the square root of 2560 is not an integer, 'a' is not an integer, meaning no integer solution for 'a' exists for this common difference.
</Path>
<Conclusion>
Integer solutions for 'a' were found for common differences d=5 (yielding a=5) and d=7 (yielding a=14), both corresponding to valid arithmetic sequences. No integer solutions for 'a' were found for common differences d=1, d=2, d=3, d=4, d=6, or d=8.
</Conclusion>
</Parallel>
Hence d=5 and d=7 yield solutions. Thus only two special sequences: third terms10 and21. Sum=31. Hence boxed answer.
**Final Answer** \boxed{31}
</Think>